right side we have a lot of stuff to get through today so I'd like to get started
오늘날 우리가 통과하는 물건을 많이 가지고 오른쪽 그래서 나는 시작하고 싶습니다
so today we're going to talk about CNN's and practice and talked about a lot of
그래서 오늘 우리는 CNN의 실천에 대해 이야기 할 것과 많이 이야기하고
really low level sort of implementation details that are really comment to get
정말 얻​​기 위해 언급되는 구현 세부 사항의 정말 낮은 수준의 종류
these things to work when you're actually training things but first as
당신이 실제로하지만 처음으로 일을 훈련 할 때 이런 일들이 작동합니다
usual we have some administrative stuff to talk about number one is that through
보통 우리는 번호 하나에 대해 이야기하는 일부 관리 물건을 그 통해이
a really heroic effort by all the TA is all the midterms are degraded so you
모든 TA에 의해 정말 영웅적인 노력은 모든 중간 고사가되도록 저하되어있다
guys should definitely thank them for that and you can either pick them up
사람은 확실히 그 대해 감사해야하고 당신도 그들을 선택할 수 있습니다
after class today or in any of these office hours that are up here also keep
클래스 오늘 또는 여기있는이 근무 시간 중 어느 한 후에도 계속
in mind that your project milestones are going to be due tonight at midnight so
그 마음에 프로젝트 이정표는 자정 때문에 오늘 밤 수 있도록거야
make sure that I hope you've been working on your projects for the last
난 당신이 마지막에 대한 귀하의 프로젝트를 진행했습니다 희망 있는지 확인
couple for the last week or so and have made some really exciting progress so
지난 주 정도에 대한 부부 등 몇 가지 정말 흥미로운 진전을
make sure to write that up and put it in the assignments tab on Dropbox no no not
그를 쓸 수 있는지 확인하고 더 더 드롭 박스에 할당 탭에서 그것을하지 넣지
on Dropbox but on the assignment tab on coursework sorry that I know this is
드롭 박스에 있지만 과정에서 할당 탭에 나는이 알고 죄송 것을
really confusing but assignments tab just like just like assignment to
정말 혼란하지만 단지 단지 등의 지정과 같은 탭을 할당
assignment two were working on grading hopefully we'll have that done sometime
할당이 잘하면 우리가 언젠가 수행해야합니다 그레이딩 작업을 하였다
this week and remember that assignment three is out so how's that been going
이번 주에 그 과제 세 가지가 너무 밖으로 기억하는 것은 어떻게이 진행되고있어
anyone anyone done okay that's good one person's done so the rest you should get
나머지는 당신이 얻을해야하므로 좋은 사람이 누구 괜찮 수행 한 사람은 이루어집니다
started because it's due in a week so we have some fun stats from the midterm so
우리는 그래서 중간에서 약간의 재미 통계를 그래서 1 주일에 의한 때문에 시작
don't freak out when you see your grade cuz we actually had this really nice
당신이 당신의 성적을 볼 때 우리가 실제로이 정말 좋은했다 사촌 흥분하지 않습니다
beautiful Gaussian distribution with a beautiful standard deviation we don't
우리가하지 않는 아름다운 표준 편차 아름다운 가우스 분포
need to bash normalize this thing it's already perfect I'd also like to point
그것이 내가 또한 지적하고 싶습니다 이미 완벽이 일을 정상화 비난해야
out that someone got up max score a hundred and three which means they got
그 사람이 일어나서에서 최대는 백 세 그들이있어 의미 점수
everything right in the bonus so that's means it wasn't hard enough to maybe
즉, 그래서 바로 보너스의 모든는 아마에 하드 충분하지 의미
we also have some per questions thats my percussion breakdown on average score
우리는 또한 질문 당 일부는 평균 점수에 내 타악기 고장을 먹으 렴이
per every single question in the midterm so if you want if you got something
당신이 뭔가를 가지고있는 경우 중간에 매 질문마다 그래서 만약 당신이 원하는
wrong and you want to see if everyone else got it wrong to you can go check on
잘못 당신은 다른 사람이 당신에게 잘못에 확인 갈 수 있어요 있는지 확인하려면
these stats leader at you're on your own time we have stats for the true false
당신이 당신의 자신의 시간에있어 이들 통계 리더 우리는 참 거짓에 대한 통계가
and the multiple choice
와 객관식
keep in mind actually fired for two of the true false we decided during grading
실제로 우리가 등급 중 결정 진정한 거짓이 해고 염두에 두어야
that they were little bit unfair to throw it out and just give you all the
그들은 그것을 버리고 당신에게 줄 약간 불공정라고 모든
points which is why two of those are a hundred percent we have these stats for
그 두 가지가 백퍼센트 왜 우리가이 통계에 대한이되는 점
all the individual questions so go ahead and have fun with those later
모든 개별 질문은 그래서 가서 그 이상으로 재미를
last time I know it's been a while but we had a midterm and we had a holiday
내가 아는 마지막으로 그것은 동안이었다 그러나 우리는 중간을했고, 우리는 휴일이 있었다
but if you can remember like over a week ago we were talking about recurrent
하지만 당신은 일주일 전에 우리가 재발에 대해 얘기했다 위에처럼 기억할 수있는 경우
networks we talked about how recurrent networks can be used for modeling
우리가 어떻게 재발 네트워크에 대해 이야기 네트워크 모델링에 사용할 수 있습니다
sequences you know normally with these feedforward networks they takin it they
이러한 피드 포워드 네트워크와 당신이 일반적으로 알고 서열 그들은 그것을 바쳐 그들이
model this keyboard function but these recurrent networks we talked about how
이 키보드 기능을 모델링하지만이 재발 네트워크를 우리는 방법에 대해 이야기
they can model different kinds of sequence problems we talked about to
그들은 우리가 이야기 순서 문제의 다른 종류를 모델링 할 수
particular implementations of recurrent networks 10 are announced and Alice and
재발 네트워크 (10)의 특정 구현이 발표되고 앨리스와
implement both of those on the assignment so you should know what they
당신이 알아야 할 수 있도록 할당에 그 모두를 구현 무엇
are we talked about how these the correct recurrent neural networks can be
우리가이 올바른 재발 성 신경 네트워크가 될 수있는 방법에 대해 이야기하다
used for language models and had some fun showing some sample generated text
언어 모델에 사용되는 일부 샘플 생성 된 텍스트를 보여주는 재미 있었다
on what is the Shakespeare and algebraic geometry that's one we talked about how
에 우리는 방법에 대해 이야기를의 셰익스피어와 대수 기하학이 무엇인지
we can combine recurrent networks with convolutional networks to do image
우리는 이미지를 할 수있는 길쌈 네트워크와 재발 네트워크를 결합 할 수 있습니다
capturing and we played a little bit this game of being RNN neuroscientists
캡처 우리는 RNN의 신경 과학자 인의 조금이 게임을
and diving into the cells of the Ardennes and trying to interpret what
그리고 아르덴의 세포로 다이빙은 무엇을 해석하려고
they're doing and we saw that sometimes we have these interminable cells that
그들은 일을하는지 우리는 때때로 우리가이 끝없는 세포를 가지고 보았다
are for example activating incited statements which is pretty cool but
꽤 멋진 문을 예를 들어 활성화를위한 선동하지만
today we're going to talk about something totally different
오늘 우리는 완전히 다른 무언가에 대해 이야기하는거야
there are three we're gonna talk about really a lot of low-level things that
우리는 낮은 수준의 것들을 정말 많이 약거야 말거야 세 가지가 그
you need to know to get CNN's working in practice so there's three major themes
세 가지 주요 테마가 그래서 당신은 실제로 CNN의 작업을 얻기 위해 알아야 할
it's a little bit of a potpourri but we're going to try to tie it together so
그것은 포푸리 약간의 그러나 우리는 그래서 그것을 함께 묶어하려고거야
the first is really squeezing all the juice that you cannot of your data so I
첫 번째는 정말 모든 주스를 압착된다 당신이 할 수없는 데이터의 정말
know a lot of you especially for projects you don't have large datasets
당신이 큰 데이터 세트를 필요가 없습니다 특히 프로젝트에 대해 많이 알고
we're going to talk about data augmentation and transfer learning which
우리는 데이터 증가 및 전송 학습에 대해 이야기 할 것중인
are two really powerful useful techniques especially when you're
당신이있어 특히이 정말 강력한 유용한 기술입니다
working with small datasets
작은 데이터 세트로 작업
we're going to really dive deep into convolutions and talk a lot more about
우리가 정말 회선에 깊은 다이빙에 대한 더 많은 이야기거야
those both how you can design efficient architectures using convolutions and
그 모두가 회선을 사용하여 효율적인 아키텍처를 설계 할 수있는 방법과
also how contributions are efficiently implemented in practice and then finally
기여 효율적으로 연습 한 후 최종적으로 구현되는 방법도
we gonna talk about something but usually gets lumped under implementation
우리는 뭔가에 대해 이야기거야하지만 일반적으로 구현에서 집중됩니다
details and doesn't even make it into papers but that stuff like someone has a
자세한 내용은 심지어 종이로하지 않고 사람과 같은 그 물건은이
CPU and GPU what kind of bottlenecks to experience and training how much you
CPU와 경험 병목 어떤 종류의 GPU하고 당신에게 얼마나 많은 훈련
distribute raining over multiple over multiple devices that's a lot of stuff
물건을 많이의 여러 장치를 통해 여러 걸쳐 비가 배포
we should get started so first let's talk about data augmentation I think
우리의 내가 생각 데이터 증가에 대해 이야기 할 수 있도록 먼저 시작해야
we've sort of mentioned this may be in passing so far in the lectures but never
우리는 종류의이 강의 그러나 결코 지금까지 전달 될 수 있습니다 언급 한
really talked about it so normally when you're training CNN's you're really
정말 당신이 CNN의 당신이 정말로있어 훈련 때 그래서 일반적으로 그것에 대해 이야기
familiar with this type of pipeline when during training you're gonna load images
때 훈련 도중 파이프 라인의이 유형에 익숙해 거 부하 이미지를이야
and labels up off the desk you're gonna pay the image through to your CNN then
당신이거야 책상 오프 최대 레이블은 다음 CNN을 통해 이미지를 지불
you're going to use the image together with the label to compute some loss
일부 손실을 계산하기 위해 라벨과 함께 이미지를 사용하는거야
function and back-propagation update the CNN and repeat former so that they
기능 및 역 전파를 업데이트 CNN과 이전의 반복 그 때문에
should be really familiar with that by now the thing about a documentation is
문서상의가에 대해 이제 일에 의해 그와 정말 잘 알고 있어야합니다
we just had one little step to this pipeline which is here so after we load
우리는 단지 우리가로드 한 후, 그래서 여기에이 파이프 라인에 하나의 작은 단계가 있었다
the image above desk we're going to transform it in some way before passing
책상 위의 이미지는 우리가 전달하기 전에 어떤 방법으로 그것을 변환하는거야
it to the CNN and this transformation should preserve the label
그것을 CNN에이 변환은 라벨을 보존한다
gonna come back propagate and the CNN so it's really simple and the trick is just
정말 간단하고 트릭 그냥 그래서 거 전파 돌아올와 CNN
what kind of Transformers you should be using such data augmentation the idea is
당신은 데이터 증가를 생각되어 사용되어야한다 변압기의 종류
really simple it's sort of this way that lets you artificially expander training
정말 간단 당신이 인위적으로 교육을 확장기 할 수 있습니다이 방법의 일종
set through clever usage of different kinds of transformations so if you
변환의 다른 종류의 현명한 사용을 통해 설정된 경우 그래서 당신
remember the computer is really seeing these images as these try and get some
이러한 시도로 컴퓨터가 정말로 이러한 이미지를보고있다 기억하고 몇 가지를 얻을 수
pixels and there are these different kinds of transformations we can make
픽셀 우리가 할 수있는 변환의 서로 다른 종류가있다
that should preserve the label but which will change all the pixels if you
그 레이블을 유지해야하지만 이는 모든 픽셀이 변경됩니다 당신이 경우
imagine like shipping that cat 1 pixel to left it's still a cat but all the
그것을 왼쪽으로 그 고양이 1 픽셀을 출하처럼 상상하는 것은 여전히​​ 고양이하지만 모든입니다
pixels are going to change that so what when you talk about a documentation
픽셀을 사용하면 문서에 대해 이야기 할 때 그래서 그 변경 예정
you're sort of imagine that you're expanding your training that these
당신은 종류의 당신이 당신의 훈련을 확대하고 상상하고
trainings and these new basic training samples be correlated but it will still
교육 및 새로운 기본 훈련 샘플은 상관 관계하지만 여전히 것
help you train models with with bigger models with preventing and this is very
당신은 방지와 더 큰 모델과 모델을 훈련하는 데 도움이 매우이다
very widely used in practice
매우 광범위하게 연습에 사용
pretty much any CNN you see that's winning competitions or doing well on
거의 모든 CNN 당신은 그 대회에서 우승거나 잘하고있어 참조
benchmarks is using some
벤치 마크는 일부를 사용하고 있습니다
station so the easiest from a bit augmentation is horizontal flipping if
비트 증가에서 가장 쉬운 그래서 역은 수평 뒤집기 경우입니다
we think this cat when you look at the mirror image the mirror images should
당신이 거울 이미지가해야 미러 이미지를 볼 때 우리는이 고양이를 생각한다
still be a cat and this is really really easy to implement an umpire you can just
여전히 고양이 일이 방금 할 수있는 심판을 구현하기 위해 정말 정말 간단합니다
do it with a single call a single line of code similarly easy and torch other
단일 통화 마찬가지로 쉽고 다른 토치 단 한 줄의 코드와 함께 할
frameworks this is really easy vary widely used something else that's very
프레임 워크이 정말 쉽다는 아주의 다른 널리 사용되는 뭔가를 변화
widely used to take random crops from the training images so a training time
널리 교육 시간 있도록 훈련 이미지에서 임의의 작물을하는 데 사용
we're gonna load up her image and we're gonna take a patch about image at a
(A)에서 이미지에 대한 패치를 가지고 우리는 그녀의 이미지를로드거야 그리고 우리는거야
random scale and location
임의의 규모와 위치
resize it to our fixed whatever size are CNN's expecting and then use that as our
우리는 CNN의는 어떤 크기를 기대하고 고정으로 크기를 조정 한 다음과 같은 것을 사용하여 우리의
training example and again this is very very widely used just give you a flavour
예를 훈련하고 다시이 아주 아주 널리 그냥 사용하는 것은 당신에게 맛을 제공
of how exactly this is used I looked up the details for residents so they
이 사용 방법을 정확하게의 전 주민에 대한 세부 사항을 그들이 그렇게 고개
actually had training time each training image resize paper sticker random number
실제로 각 교육 이미지 크기 조정 종이 스티커 난수 교육 시간을 가졌다
resize the whole image so that the shorter side is that number then sample
짧은면 해당 번호는 다음 샘플이되도록 전체 이미지 크기를 조정
of random 224 by 224 crop from the resize dimension and then use that as
다음 임의의 크기 조정 차원에서 224 작물로 224 그리고 같은 것을 사용
their training sample so that's pretty easy to implement and usually helps
훈련 샘플은 그래서 도움이 일반적으로 구현하는 데 아주 쉽게 그리고
quite a bit so when you're using this form of data augmentation usually things
꽤 당신은 데이터 증가 일반적으로 사물의 형태를 사용하고 그렇게 할 때
change a little bit test time so a training time when using this form of
약간의 테스트 시간이 양식을 사용하므로 교육 시간 변경
data augmentation the network is not really trained on full images it strain
데이터 증가는 네트워크가 정말 긴장 전체 이미지에 훈련되지 않습니다
on his crops so it doesn't really make sense or seem fair to try to force the
그의 작물에 정말 이해하거나 강제로 시도 공정하지 않는 것 때문에
network to look at the whole image as a test I'm so usually in practice when
네트워크는 내가 연습 할 때 그렇게 보통 해요 테스트로 전체 이미지를 볼 수 있습니다
you're doing this kind of random cropping for data augmentation at US
당신은 미국에서 데이터 증가에 대한 임의 자르기 이런 종류의 일을하고
time you'll have some fixed set of crops and use these for testing so very
시간 당신은 작물의 일부 고정 세트가 그래서 매우 테스트하기 위해 다음을 사용합니다
commonly you'll see that you'll see ten crops will take the upper left hand
일반적으로 당신은 당신이 왼쪽 손을 잡고 것이다 열 작물을 볼 것을 볼 수 있습니다
corner
모서리
the upper right hand corner that you bottom corners and the center gives you
당신 하단 모서리와 중심을 제공하는 오른쪽 상단 모서리
five together at the horizontal flips gives you 10 he'll take those 10 crops a
함께 수평 플립에서 오는 10 그가 그 (10) 작물 할게요 제공하는
test time passing through the network an average scores of those 10 crops so
그래서 그 (10) 작물의 네트워크를 통해 평균 점수를 통과 시험 시간
resonant actually takes those little bit one step further and actually do
공진 실제로 더 그 조금 한 단계 소요 실제로 수행
multiscale multiple scales attest time as well this is something that tends to
다중 스케일 다중 스케일이가 경향이 뭔가뿐만 아니라 시간을 증명
help performance in practice and again very easy to implement vary widely used
실제로 성능이 도움 구현 다시 아주 쉽게 널리 사용되는 다양
another thing that we usually do 48 augmentation is color generating so if
우리가 일반적으로 48 증가 할 또 다른 점은 그렇다면 컬러 생성입니다
you take this picture of a cat maybe maybe it was a little bit cloudier that
당신은 아마 어쩌면 고양이의이 사진을 찍을는 그 조금 cloudier했다
day a little bit funnier that day and if we would have taken a picture than a lot
그 날 우스운 우리가 많이보다 사진을 촬영했을 경우 하루 조금
of the colors would have been quite different so one thing that's very
색상의 너무 한 가지 아주의 그 상당히 달라졌을 것이다
common to do is just change the color a little bit of our training images before
방금 전에 색상 우리 교육의 이미지를 조금 변경하면된다하는 것이 일반적
we get to the CNN so I'm very simple way is just a change the contrast this is a
내가 아주 간단한 방법은 그냥이가있는 반면 변화입니다 해요 그래서 우리는 CNN에 도착
very easy to implement a very simple to do but actually in practice you'll see
매우 수행하는 매우 간단한을 쉽게 구현할 수 있지만, 실제로는 실제로 당신은 볼 수 있습니다
that this contract during a little bit less common and what instead you see is
이 흔하지 조금 동안 계약 대신 당신이 볼은 그
this slightly more complex pipeline using principal component analysis over
이상의 주성분 분석을 사용하여이 약간 더 복잡한 파이프 라인
all the pixels of the training data the idea is that we for each pixel in the
학습 데이터의 모든 화소 아이디어이라는 각 화소에 대한 우리
training data is this vector of length 3 an RGB and if we collect those pixels
훈련 데이터는 길이 3의 RGB이 벡터이며 우리는 그 화소를 수집하는 경우
over the entire training data that you get a sense of what kinds of colors
전체 훈련 데이터를 통해 당신은 색상의 종류의 감각을 얻을 것을
generally exist in the training data then using principal component analysis
일반적으로 다음 주성분 분석을 사용하여 트레이닝 데이터에 존재
gives us three principal component directions in color space that kind of
우리에게 색 공간이 종류의 세 가지 주요 구성 요소의 방향을 제공합니다
tell us what are the directions along which color tends to vary in the dataset
색상이 데이터 세트에서 변화하는 경향이 따라 방향이 무엇인지를 알려
so than a test at training time for color augmentation
색상 확대 술에 대한 교육 시간에 시험보다 너무
we can actually use these principal components of the color of the training
우리는 실제로 훈련의 색깔이 주요 구성 요소를 사용할 수 있습니다
site to choose exactly how to gender the color at training time this is again a
성별 훈련시에 색이 다시 얼마나 사이트 정확하게 선택할
little bit more complicated but it is pretty widely used so this type of PCA
조금 더 복잡하지만 꽤 널리 PCA 이러한 유형의 있도록 사용
driven data augmentation for color I think was introduced with Alex that
내가 생각하는 색상의 구동 데이터의 증가는 알렉스 도입 한 것
paper in 2012 and it's also used in ResNet for example so data augmentation
2012 년 종이 및 또한 예를 들어 ResNet에 사용되는 데이터의 증가 때문에
is israeli this very general thing right you just want to think about for your
이 매우 일반적인 일이 바로 당신이 단지에 대해 생각하고 싶지 이스라엘 당신의
data set what kinds of transformations do you want your class fire to be in
변환의 종류는 당신이 당신의 클래스 불에 원하는 작업 데이터 세트
various too and then you want to introduce those types of variations to
다양한 너무 그리고 당신은에 변화의 그 유형을 소개하고 싶습니다
your training data a training time and you can really go crazy here and get
훈련 데이터 교육 시간 그리고 당신이 정말로 여기에 미쳐 얻을 수 있습니다
creative and really think about your data and what types of them variances
정말 창의적이고는 데이터에 대해 생각하고 어떤 종류의 편차를
makes sense for your data so you might want to try it like maybe random
당신은 아마 랜덤처럼 그것을 시도 할 수 있습니다 귀하의 데이터에 대한 의미가 있습니다
rotations depending on your data may be rotations of a couple degrees make sense
몇도 회전 할 수있다 데이터에 따라 회전은 의미가
you could try it like different kinds of stretching and shearing to simulate
당신은 스트레칭과 시뮬레이션하기 위해 전단의 다른 종류처럼 시도 할 수 있습니다
maybe affine transformations of your data
데이터의 아마 아핀 변환
and you could really go crazy here and try to get creative and think of
그리고 당신이 정말로 여기에 미쳐과 창의력을하려고 생각할 수
interesting ways to make your data and other thing about I'd like to point out
내가 지적하고 싶은에 대한 데이터와 다른 일을 할 수있는 흥미로운 방법
is this idea of data augmentation really fits into a larger theme that now we've
데이터 증가의이 아이디어는 정말 지금 우리가했습니다 큰 테마에 맞는 것입니다
seen repeated many times throughout the course and this team is that one way
볼이 과정을 통해 여러 번 반복이 팀은 하나의 방법이다
that's really useful in practice for preventing overfitting as a regular
즉 정기적으로 overfitting 방지하기위한 연습에 정말 유용
rider is that during the fourth pass during training when we're training our
라이더는 훈련 도중 네 번째 패스 동안 우리가 훈련 할 때이다
network we had some kind of weird stochastic noise to kind of mess with
네트워크 우리와 종류 혼란에 이상한 확률 잡음의 일종했다
the network for example with data augmentation we're actually modifying
네트워크는 데이터 증가와 예를 들어 우리가 실제로 수정하고
the training data that we put into the network with things like drop out or
우리가 떨어 뜨리거나 같은 것을 사용하여 네트워크에 넣어 학습 데이터
drop connect you're taking random parts of the network and he they're setting
네트워크의 임의의 부분을 복용하고 그는 그들이 설정하는 연결 drop하여
the activations are the weights 20 randomly
프로세서의 활성화 임의로 가중치 20 아르
this also has this also appears kind of with Bosch normalization with patch
이것은 또한 이것은 또한 패치 보쉬 정상화와 종류의 표시가
normalization your normalization contents depend on the other things in
정규화하여 정규화 내용의 다른 것들에 의존
any batch so your normal and during training
그래서 정상적인 훈련 중에 배치
the same image might end up appearing in many batches with different other images
같은 이미지는 서로 다른 다른 이미지와 많은 일괄 적으로 나타나는 끝낼 수 있습니다
that actually introduces this type of noise I training time but for all of
실제로 나는 시간을 훈련 잡음 만의 모든 유형을 소개합니다
these examples a test time we averaged out this noise so for data augmentation
이러한 예는 테스트 시간 우리는 데이터 증가에 대한 그래서이 소음을 평균
we all take averages over many different samples of the training data for dropout
우리 모두가 드롭 아웃에 대한 훈련 데이터의 다양한 샘플에 걸쳐 평균을
and dropped connect you can sort of evaluate and marginalized this out in a
그리고 일종의 평가할 수를 연결 삭제하고이를 소외
little more analytically and forecasts normalization we keep keep his running
우리가 자신을 계속 실행 계속 더 분석적으로 작은 및 전망 정상화
means so I just think that's kind of a nice way to unify lot of these ideas for
그래서 난 그냥 그 이러한 아이디어를 많이 통합 할 수있는 좋은 방법의 종류 생각 의미
regularization is that when you can add noise at the forward pass and then
정규화는 다음 전진 패스에 노이즈를 추가 할 수 있습니다 때이다
marginalized over at a time so keep that in mind if you're trying to come up with
당신이 올하려는 경우 한 번에 이상 소외 너무 마음에 계속
other creative ways to regularize your networks so that's the main takeaways
그 주요 테이크 아웃을 그래서 다른 창조적 인 방법은 네트워크를 정례화하기
for data augmentation are that one it's it's usually really simple to implement
데이터 증가에 대한 하나 그것을 구현하는 것이 정말 간단하다는 있습니다
so you should almost always be using it there's not really any excuse not to
그래서 당신은 거의 항상 변명하지에 그것을 정말이 아니에요 사용해야합니다
it's very very useful especially for small datasets which i think many of you
그것은 내가 당신을 많이 생각하는 작은 데이터 세트를 위해 특별히 아주 아주 유용합니다
are using for your projects and it also fits in nicely with this framework of
프로젝트에 사용하고 또한이 프레임 워크와 멋지게에 맞는
noise at training and marginalization a test I'm so I think that's that's pretty
교육 및 소외에서 잡음이 난 테스트 그래서 나는 그 꽤의 생각
much all there is to say about data augmentation so there's any questions
많은 모든 질문이 그래서 데이터 증가에 대해 말할 수있다
about that
그것에 대해
i'm happy to talk about it now yeah a lot of time training time it would take
네 시간 훈련에 많은 시간이 걸릴 것 내가 지금 얘기 행복 해요
a lot of disk space to try to dump these things to desk so that I'm so sometimes
디스크 공간이 많이 난 그렇게 가끔 해요 있도록 책상이 일을 덤프 시도
people get creative and even have like background threads their matching data
사람들은 창의력과 배경이 그들의 일치하는 데이터를 스레드처럼도 있습니다
and documentation right so I think that's that's clear we can talk about
및 문서 바로 그래서 나는 그것이 우리가 이야기 할 수는 분명 생각
the next idea so there's this myth floating around that when you work with
다음 생각은 그래서 당신이 작업 할 때 그 주위에 떠있는이 신화있다
CNN's you really need a lot of data but it turns out that would transfer
CNN의 당신은 정말 많은 양의 데이터가 필요하지만 그 이전 것이 밝혀
learning this myth is busted so there's this really simple recipe that you can
이 정말 간단 레시피가 당신이 할 수있다, 그래서이 신화를 학습하는 파열된다
use for transfer learning and thats first you take whatever your favorite
전송 학습에 사용할 그게 먼저 당신은 무엇이든 좋아하는을
CNN architecture is Alex matter BG or what have you and you either training on
CNN 아키텍처는 알렉스 문제 BG 또는 무엇을 당신과 당신이 훈련 중 하나가 있습니다
image not yourself or you down for more commonly you download free trade bottle
이미지가 아래로 더 일반적으로에 대한 자신 또는 당신은 자유 무역 병을 다운로드하지
from the internet that's easy to do just takes 20 minutes to download many hours
불과 20 분 거리에 쉽게 인터넷이 수행하는 많은 시간을 다운로드
to train but you probably won't do that part next there's sort of two general
훈련 할 수 있지만, 일반적으로 두 종류의 거기 옆에 당신은 아마 그 부분을하지 않습니다
cases one if your data set is really small and you really don't have any
경우 하나의 데이터 세트가 정말 작고, 당신이 정말로 어떤이없는 경우
images whatsoever then you can just treat this classifier as a fixed feature
이미지는 무엇이든지 당신은 단지 고정 된 기능으로이 분류를 처리 할 수
extractor so one way to look at this is that you'll take the last layer of the
추출기 그래서이 보는 한 가지 방법은 당신이 마지막 층 할게요이다
network the soft max hospital asian model will take it away and he'll
소프트 맥스 병원 아시아 모델 멀리 걸릴 것 네트워크 그는거야
replace it with some kind of linear classifier for the task that you
작업에 대한 선형 분류의 일종으로 대체 당신을
actually care about and now you'll freeze the rest of the network and
실제로 걱정 이제 네트워크의 나머지 부분을 동결거야, 그리고
retraining only that top layer so this is sort of equivalent to just training a
해당 상위 레이어를 재교육하는 것은 그래서 이것은 일종의 그냥 훈련에의 것과 동일
linear classifier directly on top of features extracted from the network so
네트워크에서 추출 된 기능의 상단에 직접 선형 분류 그래서
what you'll see a lot of times in practice for this case is that sort of
당신이이 경우에 대한 연습에 시간을 많이 볼 것은 그런 종류입니다
as a preprocessing step you'll just dumped features to test for all of your
전처리 단계로 당신은 모든 테스트하는 기능을 덤프합니다 당신의
training images and then work entirely on top of those cast features so that
이미지를 훈련하고 있기 때문에 그 캐스트 기능의 상단에 완전히 작동
can help speed things up quite a bit and that's quite easy to use its very very
꽤 속도 일을 도와 그것은 매우 매우를 사용하여 아주 쉽게 할 수 있습니다
common and usually provides a very strong baseline for a lot of problems
일반적인 보통 많은 문제를위한 매우 강력한 기준을 제공한다
that you might encounter in practice and if you have a little bit more data than
당신은 실제로 발생하고 수도 당신보다 조금 더 많은 데이터가있는 경우
then you can actually afford to train more comfy
당신은 실제로 더 편안 훈련을 감당할 수
models so depending on the size of your dataset usually you'll freeze some parts
모델은 그래서 일반적으로 일부 부품을 고정합니다 데이터 집합의 크기에 따라
some of the lower layers of the network and then instead of retraining only the
다음 하부 네트워크 층과 일부 대신 오직 재교육의
last lair you'll pick some number of the last letters to train depending on how
마지막 은신처 당신은 방법에 따라 훈련 마지막 편지의 일부 번호를 선택합니다
larger dataset is and generally when you have a larger dataset available for
당신이 더 큰 데이터 세트를 사용할 수있을 때 더 큰 데이터 세트는 일반적이며,
training you can afford to train more of these final theirs and again if you're
당신이 훈련을 다음 최종 그들의 더 ​​많은 훈련을 감당할 다시이라면 할 수 있습니다
similar to the similar to the trick over here what you'll see very commonly is
당신은 매우 일반적입니다 볼 수 있습니다 무엇을 여기에 트릭에 비슷한 유사
that instead of actually explicitly computing this part you'll just dump
그 대신 실제로 명시 적으로이 부분을 계산 당신은 덤프합니다
these last layer features to desk and then work on this part in memory so that
이 마지막 층은 책상에 기능하고 메모리에이 부분에서 작동되도록
can speed things up quite a lot and sometimes I question that you basically
꽤 많은 일들을 빠르게 때로는 나는 기본적 것을 질문 할 수 있습니다
have to try it and see but especially for this type of small dataset will work
그것을 시도하고 볼 수 있지만 특히 작은 데이터 세트 이러한 유형의 작동해야
on instances so if you have like if you want to just do image retrieval a pretty
당신이 원한다면 그냥 할 것처럼 당신이있는 경우에 경우에 이미지가 꽤을 검색하도록
strong baseline is just use LTE distance on CNN features so it may be so this
그렇게이 될 수 있도록 강력한베이스 라인은 CNN의 기능에 LTE 거리를 사용한다
type of approach I mean harmonies how many samples you expect to need to train
당신이 훈련해야 할 것으로 예상 얼마나 많은 샘플 방식의 유형은 내가 하모니를 의미
a lot like an FBI or something and for these if you have more than if you have
당신이 당신이 가진 것보다 더 많은이 경우 연방 수사 국 (FBI)이나 뭐 같은 이들에 대한 많은
more data than you would expect to need for a nice p.m. then try that so it's
당신보다 더 많은 데이터는 그래서 좋은시는 그 시도에 필요한 기대
not at all and maybe I'm sorry yeah it depends sometimes you you actually will
전혀 어쩌면 내가 그래 당신은 가끔 미안 당신이 실제로 것입니다 의존하고있어
run through the forward pass but sometimes you just run the four pass
전진 패스를 통해 실행하지만 때로는 당신은 단지 네 개의 패스를 실행
once and dump these two desk that's kinda that's that's pretty common
한 번이 꽤 일반적입니다 좀 그건의 두 책상을 덤프
actually saves compute
실제로 계산을 절약
from random house you'll probably have different classes are you
랜덤 하우스에서 당신은 아마 당신이 다른 수업을해야합니다
Russian problem or something but then these these other intermediate layers
러시아어 문제이나 뭐하지만이 이러한 다른 중간층
you initialize from whatever was in the previous model and actually and in
당신은 실제로와의 이전 모델에 있던 어떤에서 초기화
practice when you find a nice tip it to actually do this is bad there are there
당신이 실제로 할 수있는 좋은 팁을 찾아 연습 나쁜있다가
only be two types of layers when I guess three types of layers when you're fine
당신은 괜찮아요 때 레이어의 세 가지 유형을 추측하는 경우에만 층 두 가지 유형의 수
tuning they'll be the frozen layers which you can think up as having a
그들은 당신이있는 것으로 생각할 수있는 냉동 층 수 있습니다 튜닝은
learning rate of zero there are these these new larry is that Yuri initialize
제로의 속도를 학습이 새로운 래리가 유리 초기화한다는 것이다있다
from scratch and typically those have maybe a higher learning rate but not too
처음부터 일반적으로 사람들은 너무 어쩌면 더 높은 학습 속도 만이
high maybe one tenth of what their network was originally trained west and
네트워크는 원래 서쪽 훈련이 있었는지의 높은 어쩌면 십분 및
then we'll have these intermediate layers that you are initializing from
우리는 당신이에서 초기화하는이 중간층을해야합니다
the pre train network but you're planning to modify joint optimization
전 열차 네트워크는하지만 당신은 동시 최적화를 수정할 계획하고
and fine-tuning so these intermediate layers you'll tend to be very small
당신이 경향이 있습니다 이러한 중간층 있도록 미세 조정은 매우 작게
learning rate maybe one one-hundredth of the original yeah
원래의 학습 속도 어쩌면 한 백 그래
that's some people have tried to investigate and found that generally
그 어떤 사람들은 일반적으로 그것을 조사하기 위해 노력하고 발견이다
fine tuning this type of transfer learning fine-tuning approach works
미세 조정 미세 조정 방식의 작품을 학습 전송이 유형의
better when the network was originally trained with similar types of data
더 나은 네트워크는 원래 데이터의 비슷한 유형의 훈련을받은 때
whatever that means but in fact these these very low-level features are things
어떤 것을 의미하지만, 사실이이 매우 낮은 수준의 기능을 가지 있습니다
like edges and colors and Gabor filters which are probably gonna be applicable
아마 적용 할 수 원하지되어 가장자리와 색상과 가버 필터 등
to just about any type of visual data so especially these lower level features I
단지에 대한 시각 모든 유형의 데이터 그래서 특히 이러한 낮은 수준의 기능 I에
think are generally pretty applicable to almost anything and by the way I another
생각하는 거의 모든과 방법에 의해 일반적으로 꽤 적용 할 수있는 나는 또 다른
tip that you said that you sometimes see in practice for fine-tuning is that you
당신은 당신이 때로는 미세 조정을위한 연습에서 볼 수 있다고 팁은 당신 것입니다
might actually have a multi-stage approach where first you freeze the
첫째는 동결 여기서 실제로 다단 방식을 가질 수도
entire network and then only trained this last lair and then after this last
다음 전체 네트워크에만이 지난 후에 다음이 마지막 은신처 및 훈련
layers seems to be converging then go back and actually find to indies you can
층 돌아가서 실제로 인디 당신이 할 수있는 것을 발견 한 후 수렴 것으로 보인다
sometimes have this problem that these because this last layers initialize
때로는이 때문에이 마지막 층 초기화이 문제가
randomly you might have very large gradients that kind of mess up this
무작위로 당신은 엉망이 어떤 종류의 매우 큰 경사가있을 수 있습니다
initialization so that the two ways to get around that are either freezing this
초기화는 두 가지 방법 중 하나를이 동결되는 주위를 얻을 수 있도록
at first I'm writing this converge or by having this bearing learning rate
처음에는이 수렴을 쓰는 사람이나이 베어링 학습 속도를 가짐으로써
between the two regimes of the network so this idea of transfer learning
그래서 네트워크 전송 학습이 아이디어의 두 정권 사이
actually works really well so there was a couple pretty early papers from 2013
실제로 정말 잘 몇 꽤 초기 논문은 2013 거기 때문에 작동
2014 when CNN's per started getting popular this one in particular
2014 CNN의 당은 특히이 하나의 인기가 점점 시작했을 때
astounding baseline paper was was pretty cool what they did is they took the what
그들은했다 용지가 있었다 놀라운베이스 라인 그들이 무슨 짓을했는지 매우 담담했다 무엇
at the time was one of the best
당시 최고 중 하나였다
CNN's out there was over feat they just extracted features from overseas and
해외에서 CNN의 아웃 위업에 걸쳐 있었다 그들은 단지 추출 기능과
apply these features to a bunch of different standard datasets and standard
다른 표준 데이터 세트 및 표준의 무리에 이러한 기능을 적용
problems in computer vision and they compared to these rights then the idea
컴퓨터 비전의 문제하고는 이러한 권리 아이디어에 비해
is that they compared against what was at the time these very specialized
그들은 시간이 매우 전문을에서 무엇과 비교된다
pipelines and very specialized architectures for each individual
각 개인에 대한 파이프 라인 및 매우 전문적인 아키텍처
problems and datasets and for each problem they just replaced this very
문제와 데이터 세트 및 각 문제에 대해 그들은 단지이 매우 교체
specialized pipeline with very simple linear models on top of features from
기능의 상단에 아주 간단한 선형 모델의와 전문 파이프 라인
over feet and they did this for a whole bunch of different datasets and found
피트와 서로 다른 데이터 세트의 모두를 위해 이런 짓을 발견
that in general overall these over-the-top teachers were a very very
일반적으로 전체 이러한 이상 - 더 - 상단 교사는 아주 아주이었다 있음
strong baseline and for some problems they were actually better than existing
강한베이스 라인과 몇 가지 문제들은 기존보다 실제로 더 좋았다
methods and for some problems they were
방법과 몇 가지 문제에 대해 그들이 있었다
get worse but still quite competitive so this this was a really cool paper that
이 이것은 정말 멋진 종이했을 정도로 악화하지만 여전히 매우 경쟁력 얻을 그
just demonstrated that these are really strong features that can be used in a
다만 이들에 사용될 수있다 정말 강한 특징이 있다고 입증
lot of different tasks and tend to work quite well and other paper along those
다른 작업의 많은 아주 잘 작동하는 경향이 사람들을 따라 다른 종이
lines was from Berkeley the decaf paper and decaf later became became
라인은 카페인 용지 및 디카 페인 나중에되었다되었다 버클리 출신
caffeinated and became cafe so that's that's that's kind of lineage there so
카페인과 그가가가 너무 혈통의 종류의이다, 그래서 카페가되었다
kind of the recipe for transfer learning is that there is you should think about
전송 학습을위한 조리법의 종류는 당신에 대해 생각해야 있다는 것입니다
too little to buy two matrix how similar is your data set to what the preteen
이 행렬을 구입하기에 너무 작은 무엇 초반 이었죠로 설정 데이터 방법과 유사하다
model was and how much data do you have and what should you do in those four
모델이었고, 데이터의 양을 당신이 할 당신은 그 4에 어떻게해야
different columns so generally if you have very similar data set and very
당신은 매우 유사한 데이터 세트와 매우있는 경우에 그래서 일반적으로 다른 열
little data just using the network has a fixed feature extractor and training
단지 네트워크를 사용하여 약간의 데이터는 특징 추출기 및 훈련을 수정 한
simple linear models on top of those features tends to work very well if you
이러한 기능의 상단에 간단한 선형 모델은 경우에 아주 잘 작동하는 경향이있다
have a little bit more data than you can try to try fine-tuning and try actually
당신이 미세 조정을 시도하고 실제로 시도하려고 할 수있는 것보다 조금 더 많은 데이터를 가지고
initializing network from fine tune from pre-screened weights and running
사전 심사 무게와 실행에서 미세 조정에서 네트워크를 초기화
optimization from there is another column is little tricks here in this box
다른 열이에서 최적화이 상자 여기에 약간의 트릭이다
you might be in trouble you can try to get creative and maybe instead of
당신은 당신이 창의력을 시도하고 아마 대신 할 수 있습니다 문제가 될 수 있습니다
extracting features from the very last layer you might try extracting features
맨 마지막 층으로부터 특징을 추출하면이 기능을 추출 시도 할 수 있습니다
from different layers of the continent and that can sometimes sometimes help
다른 대륙의 레이어와 그 때로는 때로는 도움이 될 수 있습니다에서
the intuition there is that maybe for something like MRI data probably these
직관이있다 어쩌면 아마도 이러한 MRI 데이터 등 뭔가
very top level features are very specific image now categories but these
매우 최고 수준의 기능은 매우 구체적인 이미지 지금 범주는하지만, 이러한
very low-level features are things like edges and stuff like that that may be
매우 낮은 수준의 기능을 할 수처럼 가장자리와 물건 같은 것들입니다
more transferable to turn on and turn on image net tech data sets and obviously
켜 분명 이미지 네트 기술 데이터 세트를 켜 더 양도
in this box you're in better shape and again you can just sort of initializing
이 상자에 당신은 더 나은 모양에있어 다시 당신은 일종의 초기화 할 수 있습니다
fine soon so another thing I'd like to point out is this idea of initializing
미세 곧 내가 지적하고 싶은 다른 일이 초기화이 좋습니다
with preteen models and fine-tuning is actually not the exception this is
초반 이었죠 모델과 미세 조정으로 실제로는 예외 아니다
pretty much standard practice in almost any larger system that you'll see in
당신이 볼 수있는 거의 모든 큰 시스템에서 거의 표준 연습
computer vision these days and we've actually seen two examples of this
컴퓨터 비전 요즘 우리는 실제로이 두 가지 예를 본 적이
already in the quarters so for example if you remember from a few lectures ago
이미 분기 예를 들어, 당신은 몇 강의 전에서 기억한다면, 그래서
we talked about object detection where we had a CNN looking at the image
우리는 이미지를보고 우리가 CNN했다 물체 검출에 대해 이야기
region proposals and this other call this all this crazy stuff but this part
지역의 제안이 다른 호출이이 모든 미친 것들하지만이 부분
was a CNN looking at the image and image captioning we had a CNN looking at the
CNN과 우리가 CNN이보고 한 이미지 및 이미지 캡션보고 있었다
image so in both of those cases though CNN's were initially is from imagefap
이미지는 이러한 경우 모두에서, 그래서 CNN의 처음 imagefap에서입니다 되었더라도
models and that really helps to solve these other more specialized problems
모델과 그 정말이 다른보다 전문적인 문제를 해결하는 데 도움이
even without a gigantic datasets and also for the image captioning model in
심지어 거대한 데이터 세트없이 또한 이미지 캡션 모델에 대한
particular part of this model includes these were demanding that you should
이 모델의 특정 부분이 당신이해야 할 것을 요구 하였다 포함
have seen by now on homework if you started on it but those weren't vectors
당신이 그것을 시작하지만 사람들은 벡터 아니었다면 숙제를 지금까지 본
you can actually initialize from something else that was maybe
당신은 실제로 아마이었다 뭔가에서 초기화 할 수 있습니다
pre-training a bunch of taxed and that can sometimes help maybe in some search
과세의 무리를 사전에 훈련하고 때로는 일부 검색에 아마 도움이 될 수 있습니다
in some situations where you might not have a lot of capturing data available
어떤 상황에서 사용 가능한 캡처 데이터를 많이 가지고하지 않을 수 있습니다 경우
yeah I'm here to help sometimes it depends on the problem depends on the
그래 나는 문제가에 따라 달라집니다에 의존 때로는 도움이 왔어요
network but it's definitely something you can try and that especially might
네트워크는하지만 확실히 당신이 시도 할 수 있습니다 뭔가하고 특히 수도
help when you're in this box but yeah that's a good trick to the takeaway
이 상자에있을 때 도움이되지만 그래 그것은 테이크 아웃에 좋은 트릭
about fine-tuning is that you should really use it it's a really good idea
대한 미세 조정은 정말 정말 좋은 생각을 사용해야한다는 것입니다
yeah so that it works really well in practice you should probably almost
그것은 실제로 정말 잘 작동하도록 그래 당신이해야 아마 거의
always be using it and to some extent you generally don't want to be training
항상 그것을 사용하고 어느 정도는 일반적으로 교육되고 싶지 않아
these things from scratch unless you have really really large data sets
처음부터이 일이 정말 정말 큰 데이터 집합이없는 경우
available in almost all of the circumstances it's much more convenient
거의 모든 상황에서 사용할 수있는 것이 훨씬 더 편리
to find to an existing model and by the way Cafe has this existing model of you
카페 기존 모델과 방식에 의해 발견하면이 기존 모델이
you can download many exist many famous image not models
당신은 많은 사람들이 많은 유명한 이미지로 모델을 존재 다운로드 할 수 있습니다
actually the residual networks the official model got released recently so
실제로 잔류 네트워크 공식 모델은 아주 최근에 출시있어
you can even download and play with it would be pretty cool and these cafe
당신도 다운로드 정말 멋진 이들 카페 것 그것으로 재생할 수 있습니다
models new models are sort of like a little bit of a standard in the
새로운 모델 모델은 일종의 표준의 약간처럼
community so you can even load cafe models into other other frameworks like
지역 사회 당신은 심지어 같은 다른 다른 프레임 워크에 카페 모델을로드 할 수 있도록
torch so that's that's something to keep in mind that these cafe models are quite
토치는 그래서 그 다음 카페 모델이 상당히 있다는 사실을 양지해야 할 무언가이다
useful right
유용 못했습니다
any any further questions on fine-tuning or transfer learning
미세 조정 또는 전송 학습에 어떤 추가 질문
yeah yeah that's quite large and lower dimensions so you might try a highly
당신이 높게을 시도 할 수 있도록 그래 그건 아주 크고 낮은 차원의
regularize linear model on top of that or you might try putting a small come
그 꼭대기에 선형 모델을 정례화하거나 작은 올 퍼팅 시도 할 수 있습니다
out on top of that maybe reduce the dimensionality you can get creative here
어쩌면 차원을 줄일 그 꼭대기에에서 여기 창조적 얻을 수 있습니다
but I think that there are there are there things you can try that might work
하지만 난 당신이 그 일을 할 수 시도 할 수있는 일이있다가 있다고 생각
for your data depending on it right so I think we should talk more about
데이터가에 따라 적합한 그래서 우리가 더 이야기해야한다고 생각
convolutions so for all these networks we've talked about it really the
회선이 모든 네트워크에 대해 우리는 그것에 대해 정말 이야기했습니다 있도록
convolutions are the computational workhorse that's doing a lot of the work
회선은 많은 작업을하고있어 계산 주력이다
and the network so we need to talk about two things about convolutions the first
네트워크는 그래​​서 우리는 회선 처음에 대해 약 두 가지를 얘기해야
is how to stop them so how can we design efficient network architectures that
우리는 효율적인 네트워크 아키텍처를 설계 할 수있는 방법 그래서 그들을 막을 방법입니다
combine many layers of convolution to achieve some some nice results so here's
여기에, 그래서 몇 가지 멋진 결과를 달성하기 위해 회선의 많은 레이어를 결합
a question suppose that we have a network that has two layers of people i
질문은 우리가 사람들의 두 개의 층이있는 네트워크를 가지고 있다고 가정 내가
three contributions as this would be the input this would be the activation map
이 같은 세 개의 기여가 입력 될이 활성화 될지도
in the first layer this would be the activation nap after two layers of
제 1 층이 두 층의 후 활성화 NAP 것
convolution the question is for an Iran on this second layer how big of a region
회선 문제는이 두 번째 층 상에이란에 대한 지역의 얼마나 큰
on the input doesn't see this was on your midterm so I i hope i hope u guys
입력이 표시되지 않습니다에이 내가 희망 나는 귀하의 중간에 있던 나는 U 너희들 희망
all know the answer to this
모두가 이에 대한 답변을 알고
anyone ok just maybe that was a hard exam question
확인 사람은 아마 그 힘든 시험 문제였다
but this is this is a five by five and it's it's pretty easy to see from this
하지만이 다섯으로 다섯입니다 그리고 그것은이에서 볼 꽤 쉽게이다
diagram why so that this neuron up to the second layer is looking at this
그림은 왜 두 번째 층까지이 신경이보고 될 수 있도록
entire volume in the intermediate where some particular in this pixel in the
일부 특정이 픽셀의 중간에서 전체 볼륨
intermediate we're looking at this three by three region in the input so when you
중간 우리가 그렇게 할 때를 입력 세 지역에 따라이 세 가지에서 찾고
average across all when you look at all of all three of these than this
이보다 다음의 세 가지를 모두 볼 때 모두에서 평균
lair this neuron in the in the second or third layer is actually looking at this
두 번째 또는 세 번째 층에있는이 신경을 은신처는 사실이보고있다
entire five by five volume in the input ok so now the question is if we had
우리가 있던 경우에 입력 다섯 부피 다섯 전체 괜찮 이제 질문은
three feet by three convolutions stacked in a row how big of a region in the
에서 지역의 얼마나 큰 행에 쌓여 세 개의 회선으로 삼피트
input what they see ya so the same kind of reason is that he's receptive field
입력 이유로 같은 종류의 그가 수용 필드가 있다고 그래서 그들은 나중에 무엇을보고
just kind of build up with successive contributions so the point here to make
여기에 포인트를 만들 수 있도록 단지 종류의 연속 공헌 구축
is that you know 33 by three convolutions actually give you a very
당신이 실제로 매우 줄 33 세에 의해 회선을 알고있다
similar representational power is my claim to a single seven by seven
비슷한 표현 능력은 하나의 일곱 일곱하여 내 주장이다
convolution so you might debate on the exact semantics of this and you could
컨볼 루션은이의 정확한 의미에 대한 토론을 할 수 있도록 당신은 할 수
try to prove theorems about it and things like that but just from an
하지만 단지에서 같은 그것에 대해 정리하고 물건을 증명하려고
intuitive sense they can 333 convolutions can represent similar types
직관적 인 감각 그들은 333 회선 비슷한 유형을 나타낼 수 있습니다
of functions as a similar seven by seven contribution since it's looking at the
그것은에서 찾고 있기 때문에 일곱 기여하여 유사한 칠 등의 기능
same input region in the input so now the idea now actually we can dig further
입력에 동일한 입력 영역 그래서 지금 생각은 지금 실제로 우리는 더 팔 수있다
into this idea and we can compare more concretely between a single 797
이 아이디어로 우리는 하나 797 사이에보다 구체적으로 비교할 수 있습니다
convolution versus a stack of 33 by three contributions so let's suppose
그래서이 가정하자 세 공헌 33의 스택 대 컨볼 루션
that we have input image that's hiw by sea and we want to have convolutions
우리는 바다로 HIW의 입력 이미지를 가지고 우리는 회선을하도록
that preserve the depth so we have see filters and we want to have them
우리가 필터를 볼 그래서 그 깊이를 보존하고 우리는 그들을 갖고 싶어
preserve heightened with so we just said patting appropriately and then we want
그래서 우리가 적절하고 우리가 원하는 두드리며 말했다으로 높게 보존 식품
to compare concretely what is the difference between a single seven by
구체적으로 비교 한 일곱의 차이에 의한 것입니다하기
seven versus a stack of three by three so first how many weeks to each of these
이러한 각각의 세 가지 그래서 처음 몇 주에 의해 세의 스택 대 칠
two things have anyone have a gas on how many weight the single seven by seven
두 가지 사람이 얼마나 많은 무게 단일 일곱 일곱으로의 가스가있다
convolution house and you can forget about biases are confusing
컨볼 루션 집과는 편견에 대해 잊을 수는 혼동
I heard I heard some summers but so my my answer I hope I got it right
나는 약간의 여름을 들었지만 나의 내 대답 나는 바로 그것을 가지고 희망을 들어
was 49 C squared as you've got the seven by seven convolution each one is looking
49 C는 각자가 찾고있는 일곱 일곱하여 회선을 가지고로 제곱했다
at a depth of see you got to see such filters so 49 C squared but now for the
볼의 깊이에서 당신은 지금 49 C 제곱 있도록 이러한 필터를 보게되었다하지만
three by three convolutions we have three layers of convolutions each one
세 개의 회선 세에 의해 우리는 회선의 세 층 각 하나가
each filter is three by three by Steve and each player has see filters when you
각 필터는 스티브으로 세 가지로 세 가지이며, 각 플레이어는 때 필터를 볼 수 있습니다
multiply that all out we see that 33 by free convolutions only has 27 C squared
모든 아웃 우리가 무료로 회선 33 만 제곱 (27) C가 볼 것을 곱
parameters and assuming that we have Ray Lewis after between each of these
매개 변수와 우리는 이러한 각각의 사이에 후 레이 루이스가 있다고 가정
contributions we see that the stack up 33 by three convolutions actually has
기여는 우리는 세 개의 회선으로 최대 33 스택이 실제로 있는지 참조
fewer parameters which is good and more nonlinearity which is good for this kind
이런 종류의 좋은 좋은 더 비선형이다 적은 수의 매개 변수
of gives you some intuition for why a stack of three by of multiple three by
의 여러 세에 의해 당신에게 세 가지의 이유 스택에 대한 몇 가지 직관을 제공합니다
three convolutions might actually be preferable to a single seven by seven
세 개의 회선은 실제로 하나의 일곱 칠로하는 것이 바람직 할 수있다
competition and we can actually take this one step further and think about
경쟁은 우리가 실제로 더이 한 단계 걸릴에 대해 생각 할 수 있습니다
not just the number below normal parameters but actually honey floating
하지 일반 매개 변수 아래 단지 수 있지만, 실제로 꿀 부동
point operations to these things take so anyone have a gas for how many
이 일에 소수점 연산 그래서 사람이 얼마나 많은 가스가 걸릴
operations these things to take just now sounds hard writes actually this is
이러한 일들이 지금 수행 할 작업이이 실제로 하드 쓰기 소리
pretty easy because for each of these filters were gonna be using it at every
때문에 이러한 필터 각각에 대해 매우 쉽다는 거의 모든 IT를 사용했다
position in the end in the image so actually the number of multiply ads is
이미지의 단부에 위치하므로 실제 곱셈의 광고의 수는
just gonna be Heights times with times the number of burnable filters so you
단지거야 시간이 Heights의 배 가연성 필터의 수를 당신 때문에
can see that actually over here again not only do we have some between
실제로 여기에 그것을 볼 수 있습니다 다시뿐만 아니라 우리 사이에 있나요
comparing between these two the seven by seven action not only has more learnable
이 두 가지 사이에 일곱으로 칠 작업을 비교하는 것은뿐만 아니라 더 많은 학습 가능이
parameters but it actually costs a lot more to computers well so the stack of
매개 변수하지만 실제로 잘 스택 있도록 더 많은 컴퓨터에 비용
33 by frequent allusions again gives us more nonlinearity for less compute so
자주 암시로 (33)는 다시 적은 컴퓨팅 우리에게 더 비선형 성을 제공하므로
that kinda gives you some intuition for why actually having multiple layers of
그 좀 당신에게 왜 실제로 여러 층을 갖는 몇 가지 직관을 제공합니다
three bay three convolutions is actually preferable to large filters but then you
세 베이 세 회선하지만 다음 큰 필터 실제로 바람직하다
can think of another question you know we've been pushing towards smaller and
우리가 작은쪽으로 밀어 봤는데 알고 또 다른 질문을 생각할 수 있으며,
smaller filters but why stop at three by three right we can actually go smaller
작은 필터하지만 왜 바로 우리가 실제로 작은 갈 수있는 세 가지에 의해 세에서 정지
than that may be the same logic would expand
그건있을 수 있습니다보다 같은 논리 확장 것
shaking your head you don't believe it that's true it's true you don't get the
머리를 흔들어 당신은 당신이 얻을하지 않습니다 그것은 사실 그 사실을 믿지 않는다
receptive field so actually what we're going to do here is compared to a single
우리가 여기서 할거야 그래서 실제로 무엇을 수용 필드는 단일 비교된다
33 convolution versus a slightly fancier architecture the bottleneck architecture
약간 애호가 아키텍처 병목 아키텍처 대 33 회선
so here we're gonna assume I can input of HW see and hear we can actually do
그래서 여기에 우리는 내가 HW의 입력이보고 우리가 실제로 할 수있는들을 수있는 거 가정하고
this is a cool trick we do a single one-by-one convolution with see over to
이것은 우리가까지 볼 수있는 단일 하나씩 회선을 멋진 트릭
filters to actually reduce the dimensionality of the volume so now this
필터는 실제로 지금이 볼륨의 차원을 줄이기 위해
thing is going to have the same spatial extent but half the number of features
것은 동일한 공간 범위이지만 기능 절반이 예정
in-depth now after we do this bottleneck we're gonna do a three by three
심층 지금 우리는거야이 병목을 수행 한 후 3 × 3 할
convolution at this reduced dimensionality so now this this three by
이 감소 차원에서 컨볼 루션 지금이이 세 가지에 의해
three convolution takes over to input features and produces over to output
세 개의 회선 입력 기능을 통해 받아 출력에 이상 발생
features and now we restore the dimensionality with another one by one
기능과 이제 우리는 하나 다른 하나를 사용하여 차원을 복원
convolution to go from see over to back to see this is kind of a kind of a funky
이 펑키 한 가지 종류의 볼 백업을 통해 볼에서 회선은 이동
architecture this idea of using one-by-one convolutions everywhere is
아키텍처는 하나씩 회선을 사용하는이 아이디어는 어디 에나있다
sometimes called network and network because it has this intuition that
그것은이 직관을 가지고 있기 때문에 때로는 네트워크와 네트워크라는 것을
you're a one-by-one convolution is kinda similar to sliding a fully connected
당신은 하나씩 회선이 완전히 연결 슬라이딩에 좀 유사하다있어
network over each part of your input volume and this idea also appears in
당신의 입력 볼륨의 각 부분에 걸쳐 네트워크와이 아이디어도 나타납니다
Google Matt and in ResNet this idea of using these one-by-one bottleneck
구글 매트와이 하나씩 병목 현상을 사용 ResNet이 생각
contributions so we can compare this this bottleneck sandwich to a single
기여 그래서 우리는 하나이이 병목 샌드위치를​​ 비교할 수 있습니다
three by three convolution with C filters and run through the same logic
C 필터와 세 개의 회선에 의해 세와 같은 논리를 통해 실행
so I won't I won't force you to computers in your heads but you'll have
그래서 나는 당신의 머리에있는 컴퓨터에 강제하지 않습니다하지만 당신은 할 수 있습니다
to trust me on this
이 날 믿어하기
that this bottleneck stack has three and a quarter C squared parameters where is
이 병목 스택은 세 가지를 가지고 어디 분기 C는 매개 변수를 제곱 것을
this one over here has nine C squared parameters and again if we're sticking
여기이 사람은 우리가 고집하는 경우 구 C가 다시 매개 변수를 제곱있다
rallies in between each of these contributions than this bottleneck
이 병목 이상이 기여 각각의 사이에 집회
sandwich is giving us more more nonlinearity for fewer number of
샌드위치는 적은 수의 우리에게 더 많은 비선형 성을주고있다
parameters and actually as we similar to we saw on the three by three versus
우리는 실제로 같은 우리 유사한 매개 변수 및 대 세에 의해 세에서 본
seven by seven the number of parameters is tied directly to the computation so
일곱으로 칠 매개 변수의 수는 그렇게 계산에 직접 연결되어
this bottleneck sandwich is also
이 병목 샌드위치도
much faster to compute so this to this idea of one-by-one bottlenecks has
훨씬 빠른 하나씩 병목 현상이 아이디어에 따라서이를 계산한다
received quite a lot of usage recently in Google Matt and especially yeah so
구글 매트에서 최근에 사용 꽤 많이 받고 특히 그래 그렇게
you might think of it as you sometimes you think of it as as a projection from
당신은 때때로 당신이에서 투사로로 생각 당신은 그것의 생각
like a lower dimensional feature back to a higher dimensional space and then if
다시 더 높은 차원 공간에 다음의 경우 낮은 차원 기능 등
you think about stacking many of these things on top of each other as happens
당신은 어떻게 서로의 상단에 이런 일을 많이 쌓아 생각
and residents than than you have been coming immediately after this one is
당신이 한 직후오고 것보다보다 주민
going to be another one by one
하나 또 하나가 될 것
you're kind of stuck in many many one people one by one convolutions on top of
당신은 가지 위에 많은 많은 한 사람들 하나 하나 회선 붙어있어
each other and one-by-one convolution is a little bit like sliding a fully a
서로 하나씩 회선 조금 슬라이딩 같이하는 완전히
multi-layer fully connected network over each double channel to think maybe think
각각의 이중 채널을 통해 다층 완전히 연결 네트워크는 아마 생각 생각하는
about that when a little bit but it turns out that actually you don't really
그것에 대해 때 조금하지만 실제로 당신이 정말 안 밝혀
need the spatial extent and even just comparing the sandwich to a single three
공간적 범위를 필요로하고, 심지어 단 하나의 세 가지로 샌드위치를​​ 비교
by three Khans you're sort of having the same input output volume sizes but
세 Khans하여 정렬의 동일한 입력 출력 볼륨 크기를 갖는하고 있지만,
what's more nonlinearity and cheaper to compute and animal parameters so they're
더 비선형 그들이있어 그래서 저렴 계산과 동물 매개 변수는 무엇입니까
all kind of nice features but there's there's one problem with this is that
이 것입니다 모든 좋은 기능의 종류 만이 거기에 하나의 문제입니다
that's we're still using a three by three convolution in there somewhere and
즉, 우리는 여전히 어딘가에서 3 × 3 회선을 사용하고 그리고
you might wonder if we if we really need this and the answer is No it turns out
우리는 우리가 정말이 필요하면 경우에 당신이 궁금해 할 수 대답은 그것이 나오는 것에 없음입니다
so one crazy thing that I've seen recently is that you can you can factor
내가 최근에 본 적이 한 미친 것은 당신이 당신이 인수 분해 할 수 있다는 것입니다
the street by three convolution in 2003 by one and won by three and compared to
하나 2003 년에 세 개의 회선으로 거리와 세에 의해 원에 비해
the single three by three convolution this ends up saving you some parameters
단일 세에 의해 세 개의 회선이 몇 가지 매개 변수를 저장 끝
as well so that you might if you really go crazy you can come by in this one by
뿐만 아니라 당신이 정말로 당신으로이 일에 의해 올 수 미쳐 경우 수도 있기 때문에
three and three by one together with this bottleneck an idea and things just
세와 함께이 병목와 하나 세 생각과 사물 단지
get really cheap and that's basically what Google has done in their most
정말 저렴받을 수 있도록 구글이 가장에서 무슨 짓을했는지 기본적이다
recent version of Inception so there's this kind of crazy paper rethinking the
인 셉션의 최신 버전은 그렇게 미친 종이의이 종류가를 다시 생각있다
inception architecture for computer vision where they play a lot of these
그들이이 많이 재생 컴퓨터 비전에 대한 개시 아키텍처
crazy tricks about factoring convolutions in weird ways and having a
이상한 방법으로 회선을 감안하고있는에 관하여 미친 트릭
lot of one-by-one bottlenecks and then projections backup to different
다른에 하나씩 병목 현상을 많이하고 예측 백업
dimensions and then if you thought the original Google met with with their
당신이 생각 치수 다음 경우 원래 구글과 만나 자신의
inception module was was crazy
처음 모듈은 미친이었다
this one's these are the inception modules that Google is now using in
이 일이 구글이 지금에 사용하고있는 개시 모듈입니다 것
their newest inception at
그들의 최신 개시
and the interesting features here are that they have these one-by-one
여기에 흥미로운 기능은 다음 하나씩을 가지고 있습니다
bottlenecks everywhere and make sure you have these asymmetric filters to against
모든 곳에서 병목 현상이에 대한 이러한 비대칭 필터를 가지고 있는지 확인
Avon computation so this stuff is not super widely used yet but it's it's it's
에이 계산 그래서이 물건은 슈퍼 널리 아직 사용되지 않지만, 그것은 그것의의의
out there and it's a Google Matt psychotics it something cool to mention
거기 그것은 구글 매트는 그것을 언급 멋진 무언가를 정신병이야
so quickly recap from convolutions and how to stack them is that it's usually
이렇게 빨리 회선에서 개괄하고는 보통의 것입니다 스택하는 방법
better instead of having a single large convolution with a large filter size
대신 큰 필터 크기의 하나의 큰 회선을 갖는의 더 나은
it's usually better to break up into multiple smaller filters and that even
그것은 여러 개의 작은 필터로하고 있음을 해체하는 것이 더 나은에도
maybe helps explain the difference between something like BGG which has
어쩌면이 BGG 같은 사이의 차이를 설명하는 데 도움이
many many three by three filters with something like Alex net that have fewer
적은이 알렉스 그물 같은 많은 많은 3 × 3 필터
smaller filters and other thing that's actually become pretty common i think is
실제로 내가 생각 꽤 공통되고있다 작은 필터와 다른 것은
this idea of one by one bottle necking you see that in both versions of Google
당신을 네킹 한 병 하나의이 아이디어는 볼 구글의 두 버전에서
not and also in ResNet and that actually helps you save a lot on parameters I
되지도 ResNet에서 그것은 실제로 당신이 매개 변수를 많이 절약 할 수 있습니다 I
think that's a useful trick to keep in mind and this idea of factoring
이 염두에 두어야 할 유용한 트릭과 인수 분해의이 아이디어 생각
convolutions into these asymmetric filters i think is maybe not so widely
내가 생각이 비대칭 필터로 회선 어쩌면 너무 광범위하지 않습니다
used right now but it may become more commonly used in the future I'm not sure
지금 사용하지만, 더 일반적으로 미래에 사용되는 잘 모르겠어요 될 수 있습니다
and the basic over overarching theme for all of these tracks is that it lets you
이러한 모든 트랙에 대한 지배적 인 테마를 통해 기본은 당신을 할 수 있다는 것입니다
have fewer learnable parameters and fewer and less compute and more
적은 학습 가능 매개 변수 적은 적은 컴퓨팅 등을 가지고
nonlinearity which are all sort of nice features to having your architectures
좋은 기능을 모든 종류의 당신의 아키텍처를 데있다 비선형
such as any questions about these these convolution architecture designs to
이러한 이러한 이러한 회선 아키텍처 설계에 대한 질문으로
bring her too obvious
그녀가 너무 분명 가져
ok so then the next thing is that once you've actually decided on how you want
확인 그래서 그 다음 것은 당신이했습니다되면 실제로 당신이 원하는 방법에 대한 결정이다
to wire up your stack of convolutions you actually to compute them and this
회선의 스택을 묶는 당신은 실제로 그들을 계산하고이하는
there's actually been a lot of work on different ways to implement
실제로 구현하는 여러 가지 방법에 많은 일이있었습니다
contributions we asked you to implement of the assignments using for loops and
기부는 우리가 루프를 사용하여 과제의 구현을 물어
that as you may have guessed doesn't scale too well so this a pretty a pretty
당신은 너무 잘 확장되지 않습니다 추​​측 수 있으므로이 너무 예쁜 예쁜
easy approach that's pretty easy to implement is this idea of a name to call
구현하기가 매우 쉽다 쉬운 방법은 이름의이 아이디어는 호출하는 것입니다
method so the intuition here is that we know matrix multiplication is really
방법은 그래서 여기 직관은 우리가 행렬 곱셈 정말 알고있다
fast and pretty much any computing architecture out there someone has
빠르고 거기에 누군가가 거의 모든 컴퓨팅 아키텍처
written a really really well optimized matrix multiplication retainer library
정말 정말 잘 최적화 행렬 곱셈 고정 라이브러리를 작성
so the idea of him to call is stinking well given that matrix multiplication is
그래서 전화를 그의 생각이 잘 행렬 곱셈이 주어진 악취된다
really fast
정말 빠른
is there some way that we can take this convolution operation and recast as a
우리는이 컨볼 루션 연산을하고 같은 개주 수있는 몇 가지 방법이있다
matrix multiply and it turns out that this is actually pretty somewhat easy to
행렬 곱셈과 이것이 꽤 다소 쉽게가 있음을 밝혀
do once you think about it so the idea is that we have an input volume that's
아이디어가 그래서 당신은 우리의 입력 볼륨을 가지고 그것에 대해 생각하면
hiw by sea and we have a filter bank of convolutions of convolutional filters
바다 HIW 우리는 컨볼 루션 필터 회선의 필터 뱅크가
each one of these is going to be a case-by-case by see volume so it has a
그것은이 때문에 이들 각각 볼 볼륨으로 사례 별을 될 것입니다
case-by-case receptive field and adaptive see two matched to match the
사례 별 수용 필드와 적응 두가 일치 일치 참조
input over here and we're gonna have to deal with these filters and then we want
입력 여기에 우리는거야 것은 이러한 필터 처리해야하고 우리가 원하는
to turn this into a into a matrix multiply problem so the idea is that
아이디어는 점이다 있도록 행렬 곱셈 문제로이 점을 켭니다
we're going to take one of their we're going to take the first receptive field
우리는 우리가 먼저 수용 필드를 취할려고하고 자신의 일을하는거야
of the image which is gonna be this kay by Kay by CEE region in the region in
거 지역에서 CEE 영역에 의해 케이하여이 케이를 할 수있는 이미지의
the end up in football you I'm going to reshape it into this column of case
축구에서 최종까지 나는 사건이 컬럼에 그것을 바꿀거야 당신
whereby see elements and then we're going to repeat this for every possible
이에 요소를 확인하고 우리는 가능한 모든이를 반복하는거야
receptive field in the image so we're going to take this little guy I'm going
이미지의 수용 필드 그래서 우리는 내가 갈거야이 작은 사람을거야
to shift him over all possible regions in the image and here I'm just saying
이미지에 가능한 모든 영역에 걸쳐 그를 이동하고 여기에 그냥 말하는거야
that there's going to be maybe end region and different receptive field
될 것이 아마 지역과 다른 수용 필드를 종료하는 것이
locations so now we've taken our image and we've taken reshaped into this giant
위치는 지금 우리는 우리의 이미지를 촬영했습니다 우리는이 거대한으로 재편 촬영했습니다
matrix oh and by I mean and in my case whereby see anyone see what a potential
매트릭스 오 누구나 볼 볼 수있다 내 말 및 내 경우 어떤 가능성을
problem with this maybe
이 아마와 문제
yeah that's true so best this tends to use a lot of memory right so many
그래, 그게 사실은 그래서 최선이 바로 많은 메모리를 많이 사용하는 경향이
elements in this volume if it appears and multiple receptive fields then it's
이 책의 요소가 나타나는 경우 여러 수용 필드 다음이다
going to be duplicated in multiple of these columns so and this is going to
가고 그래서 이러한 열 여러 중복되는 및이에 가고
get worse the more overlap there is between your receptive fields but it
당신의 수용 필드하지만 사이가 overlap은 더 더를 얻을 수
turns out that in practice that's actually not too big of a deal and it
실제로이 실제로 거래의 너무 큰 아니에요 및 밝혀 그
works fine then we're gonna run a similar check on these convolutional
우리는거야이 길쌈에 유사한 검사를 잘 실행하고 작품
filters so if you remember what a convolution is doing we want to take
필터는 그래서 만약 당신이 회선 우리가 먹고 싶어 무엇을하고 있는지 기억
each of these convolutional weights and take our products with each
이러한 길쌈 무게의 각 각으로 우리의 제품을
convolutional weight against each receptive field location in the image so
이미지 때문에 각 수용 필드 위치에 대한 길쌈 무게
each of these convolutional weights is is this kay by Kay buy seats answer so
이 길쌈 무게의 각이 케이에 의해이 케이 것은 좌석이 그렇게 대답 구입
we're going to reshape each of those to be a case where by Ciro now we have D
우리는 치로로 이제 우리는 D를 경우로 그 각각을 바꿀거야
filters so we got a deal by case whereby seat matrix now this is great
좌석 행렬은 지금이 좋은해진다 필터 그래서 우리는 경우에 의해 계약을 얻었다
now this guide contains all the recep each each column as a receptive field we
지금이 가이드는 수용 필드로 각 열의 모든 레셉 각을 포함 우리
have one column receptive field in the image and now this matrix has one has
이미지에 하나의 컬럼 수용 필드가 지금이 행렬은 하나가있다
one each row is a different weight so now we can easily compute all of these
하나의 각 행은 우리가 쉽게이 모든 계산할 수 해주기 때문에 다른 무게
inner products all at once with the single matrix multiply and I apologize
내부의 제품은 한 번에 하나의 행렬 곱 나는 사과
for these dimensions not working out the probably should swap is to make it more
이러한 차원의 아마 교체해야 밖으로 작동하지 않는 것은 더 만드는 것입니다
obvious but I think you get the idea so this this gives und by end result that
분명하지만 난 당신이 아이디어를 얻을 생각 때문에이이 최종 결과에 의해 싶게를 제공하는
that D is our number of output filters and that n is for all the receptive
그 D 출력 필터의 우리의 수를하고, n은 모두 받아 들일입니다
field locations in the image then you play a similar trek to take this and
이미지 필드의 위치는 다음이 걸릴 비슷한 여행을 재생
reshape it into your interior 3d appetizer you can actually stand this
실제로이 참을 수있는 실내 3D 전채로 모양을 변경
too many batches quite easily if you have a mini batch of any of these
아주 쉽게 당신이 이들의 미니 배치가있는 경우 너무 많은 배치
elements you just add more rows and how one set of rows per me back element this
요소는 당신은 행의 한 세트 나 다시 요소이 당 더 많은 행과 방법을 추가
actually is pretty easy to implement so yeah
실제로 그래 그렇게 구현하는 매우 간단합니다
depends that-that's then it depends on your implementation right but then you
그 것을 - 그 다음 구현 오른쪽에 달려 있지만, 다음의 따라 달라집니다
have to worry about things like memory layout and stuff like that but sometimes
그 때로는 같은 메모리 레이아웃 및 물건 같은 것들에 대해 걱정할 필요가
you even do that reshape operation on the GPUs you can do it in parallel but
당신도 당신이 병렬로 그것을 할 수있는 GPU에서 그 모양 변경 작업을 수행하지만,
as a as a case study so this is really easy to implement so a lot of if if if
그래서 이것은 정말 쉬운 사례 연구로는 너무 많이 구현하는 등의 경우 경우 경우
you don't have a convolution technique available and you need to implement one
사용 가능한 컨벌루션 기술이 없어 하나를 구현해야
passed this is probably the one to choose and if you look at actual cafe in
이것은 아마도 선택할 수있는 하나 통과하면 실제 카페를 보면
earlier versions of cafe this is the method that they used for doing
카페의 이전 버전이 그들이 무엇에 사용되는 방법이다
contributions so this is the convolution forward code for the GPU conflict the
기부금이는 GPU 충돌에 대한 회선 앞으로 코드가 있도록
native GPU convolution in you can see in this red chunk they're calling into the
당신의 기본 GPU의 컨볼 루션들은으로 전화하는거야이 붉은 덩어리를 볼 수 있습니다
same to call method is taking their input image rights this is taking their
전화를 같은 방법이 복용 그들의 입력 영상 권한을 가지고 그들의
input image somewhere this is so this is their intention and then they're going
입력 영상 어딘가에이 그래서 이것은 그들의 의도 된 후 그들은거야
to reshape this calling the same to call method and then store it in this in this
이것은이이 방법으로 호출하고이를 저장하는 동일한 전화 재정비
column GPU tenser than they're gonna take to a matrix matrix multiply calling
그들이 호출 곱 행렬 행렬에 거 가지고있어보다 열 GPU의 tenser
it could last through the matrix multiply and then a bias so that's
즉, 그래서 그것은 곱셈 후 바이어스 행렬을 지속 할 수
that's how that's i mean these things tend to work quite well in practice and
그 그 내가 이러한 일들이 실제로 아주 잘 작동하는 경향이 의미의 방법과
also has another case study if you remember the fast layers we gave you any
당신은 우리가 당신 하나를 준 빠른 레이어를 기억한다면 또 다른 사례 연구가
assignments actually uses this exact same strategy so here we actually do nm
과제 실제로 우리가 실제로 나노 수행 그래서 여기에이 동일한 전략을 사용
to call operation was some crazy numpy tricks and then now we can actually do
작업을 호출하는 지금 우리가 실제로 할 수있는 다음 어떤 미친 NumPy와 트릭이었고,
the convolution inside The FAST layers with a single call to the numpy matrix
NumPy와 매트릭스에 단일 통화와 FAST 층 내부의 회선
multiplication and you sign your homework this usually gives me a couple
곱셈 당신과이 보통 나에게 몇 가지를 제공합니다 숙제에 서명
hundred times faster than using for loops this actually works pretty well
이 꽤 잘 작동 루프를 사용하는 것보다 더 빨리 백 번
and it's it's pretty easy to implement any questions about him to call
그리고는 전화 그에 대해 질문을 구현하는 데 아주 쉽게이다
think about it a little bit but if you think if you think really hard you'll
그것에 대해 조금 생각하지만, 당신이 생각하는 경우에 당신이 정말 열심히 생각하면 당신은거야
realize that the backward pass on a convolution is actually also a
컨볼 루션의 뒤로 패스도 실제로 실현
convolution which you may have figured out a few if you're thinking about it on
당신이 그것에 대해 생각한다면 당신은 몇 가지 알아 낸 수 컨볼 루션
your homework but the backward pass a convolution is actually also a type of
당신의 숙제하지만 이전 버전과는 회선도 실제로의 유형입니다 통과
convolution over the over the upstream gradients you can actually use a similar
상류 구배를 통해 실제로 비슷한을 사용할 수있는 이상 컨볼 루션
type of image to call method for the tobacco passes well the only trick there
담배가 아니라 유일한 트릭을 전달하기위한 이미지의 유형은 메소드를 호출합니다
is that one once you do in a backward pass you need to some gradients from
당신이 뒤로 패스 할 후에는 일부 그라디언트에 필요 한 것입니다
across overlapping receptive fields in the upstream so you need to be careful
상류에서 수용 필드를 중복 통해 당신은주의해야하므로
about the call Tim you need to summon the call Tim in the backward pass and
통화 팀에 대해 당신이 뒤로 패스에서 호출 팀을 소환 필요
you can actually check out in the fast lane is on the homework implements that
숙제는 것을 구현에 실제로 빠른 차선에서 확인하실 수 있습니다 것은
too although actually further in the fast layers on the homework the call tim
너무 실제로 비록 더 숙제를 호출 팀에 빠른 레이어
is in sight on I couldn't find a way to get it fast enough in there's actually
실제로 거기에 내가 충분히 빨리 그것을 얻을 수있는 방법을 찾을 수 없습니다에 눈에
another way that sometimes people use for convolutions and that's this idea of
때로는 사람들이 회선 사용하고는이 아이디어 또 다른 방법
a Fast Fourier Transform so if you have some memories from like a signal
당신이 신호 등으로부터 추억이있는 경우 고속 푸리에 그래서 변환
processing class or something like that you might remember this thing called the
처리 클래스 또는 호출이 일을 기억 수도 같은
convolution theorem met says that you if you have two signals and you want to
충족 회선 정리는 두 개의 신호를 가지고 있다면 당신은 당신이 원하는 것을 말한다
call them either discreetly are continuously with another girl then
하나 신중하게 한 후 다른 여자와 계속되어 그들에게 전화
taking a convolution of these two signals is the same as rather the
이들 두 신호의 콘볼 루션을 복용하면 오히려와 동일
Fourier transform of the convolutions is the same as the elements product of the
회선의 푸리에 변환은 요소 제품과 동일
Fourier transforms so if you have you unpacked out and stare the symbols I
당신은 당신이 밖으로 압축을 푼 가지고 기호를 응시 그래서 만약 푸리에 변환 I
think it'll make sense and if also you might remember from again a signal
이 의미가있을 거라 생각하고 또한 경우 다시 신호에서 기억하고 있습니다
processing class or an algorithm class there's this amazing thing called the
처리 클래스 또는 알고리즘 클래스 호출이 놀라운 일이있다
fast Fourier transform that actually likes lets us to compute Fourier
고속 푸리에 실제로 좋아 푸리에 변환을 계산하기 위해 우리가 할 수 변환
transforms an inverse Fourier transforms really really fast
역 푸리에 정말 정말 빠른 변환 변환
you may have seen it bears versions of this in one day in 2d and they're all
당신은 2D에서 하루에이 버전의 곰 볼 수 있으므로 그들은 모든 것
really fast so we can actually applied a stricter convolutions so the way this
정말 빠른 그래서 우리는 실제로 엄격한 회선을 적용 할 수있는 방법이 너무
works is that first we're going to compute use the Fast Fourier Transform
작동 처음 우리가 고속 푸리에 변환을 사용하여 계산하는거야 것입니다
to compute the Fourier transform the weights also compute the Fourier
푸리에 푸리에을 계산에도 가중치를 계산하는 변환
transform of our activation map and now in Fourier space we just do an element
우리의 활성화지도의 변환 지금 푸리에 공간에서 우리는 단지 요소를 할
multiplication which is really really fast and efficient and then we just come
정말 정말 빠르고 효율적이며 다음 우리가 올 곱셈
again and use the pass for a transformed to do the inverse transform the output
다시의 패스를 사용하여 상기 역 출력을 변환 할 변환
of that elements product and that implements convolutions for us in this
그 요소 제품의이에 우리를 위해 회선을 구현
kinda cool fancy clever way and this is actually been used and face some folks
멋진 영리한 방법 좀 시원하고이 실제로 사용하고 몇몇 사람에 직면하고있다
that Facebook had a paper about this last year and they actually released a
페이스 북이 작년에 관한 논문을했다 그리고 그들은 실제로 출시 것을
GPU library to do this
GPU 라이브러리는이 작업을 수행하는
compute these things but the sad thing about these Fourier transforms this that
이 일을 계산하지만, 이러한 푸리에에 대한 슬픈 일이 변환이
they actually give you really really big speedups over other methods but really
그들은 실제로 당신에게 정말 다른 방법하지만 통해 정말 큰 속도 향상을 제공
only four large boulders and when you're working on these small three by three
당신은이 작은 3 × 3에 최선을 다하고 네 개의 큰 바위와 때
filters the overhead of computing the Fourier transform just towards the
푸리에 변환을 계산하는 오버 헤드를 향해 바로 변환 필터
computation of doing the computation directly in the in the input pixel space
입력 화소 공간에서 직접 연산을하는 연산
and as we just talked about earlier in the lecture small contributions are
우리가 강의에 앞서 이야기로 작은 기여는
really really nice and appealing and great for lots of reasons so it's a
그것은을, 그래서 많은 이유에 대해 정말 정말 멋지고 매력과 큰
little bit of a shame that this for a trick doesn't work out too well impact
트릭이 너무 잘 영향을 작동하지 않습니다 수치의 조금
us but if for some reason you do want to compute really large contributions then
우리하지만 어떤 이유로 경우 당신은 정말 큰 기여를 계산하고 싶어
this is something you can try yeah
이 그래 당신이 시도 할 수있는 일입니다
too involved in stuff but I imagine if you think it's a problem is probably a
너무 물건에 관여하지만 당신이 문제가 아마이다 생각하면 내가 상상
problem
문제
ya another thing to point out is that one kind of balance out about Fourier
나중에 지적하는 또 다른 한가지는 그 푸리에에 대한 균형 아웃 한 종류의
transforms conclusions is that they don't handle striding too well so far
결론을 변환하는 것은 그들이 지금까지 너무 잘 월쯤 처리하지 않는다는 것입니다
normal computer with your computing strident convolutions in sort of normal
정상의 종류에 계산 귀에 거슬리는 회선과 일반 컴퓨터
input space you only compute a small subset of those in our products so you
입력 공간 만 우리의 제품에 사람들의 작은 하위 집합을 계산하면 이렇게
actually save a lot of computation when you strike the convolutions
당신이 회선을 공격 할 때 실제로 계산을 많이 저장
directly on the input space but the way you tend to implement strident
직접 입력 공간하지만 방법에 당신은 귀에 거슬리는 구현하는 경향이
convolutions in Fourier transform space is you just compute the whole thing and
푸리에의 회선 공간이 당신은 단지 전체를 계산한다 변환 및
then you throw out part of the data so that ends up not being very efficient so
그 때문에 매우 효율적되지 않는 끝, 그래서 당신은 데이터의 일부를 밖으로 던져
there's another trick that has not really become too I think too widely
정말 너무 넓게 생각도하게되지 않은 또 다른 트릭이있다
known yet but I really liked it so I thought I wanted to talk about that so
알려진 아직하지만 난 정말 그렇게 내가 그것에 대해 그렇게 얘기하고 싶었 생각 좋아
you may remember from algorithms class something called stratton's algorithm
당신은 스트래튼의 알고리즘이라는 알고리즘 클래스에서 뭔가 기억하고있다
right there's this idea that when you do a naive matrix multiplication of to end
바로 당신의 순진 행렬 곱셈을 수행 할 때 종료하는 것이이 아이디어가있다
by and matrices kind of if you count up although although all the modifications
에 의해 종류의 행렬 당신은 카운트 경우 비록 모든 수정 있지만,
and additions that you need to do it's going to take about its gonna take any
당신이 그것을 할 필요가 추가는거야 어떤을 정도 걸릴 것
cute operations and stratton's algorithm is this like really crazy thing we
귀여운 운영 및 스트래튼의 알고리즘은 정말 미친 것처럼 이것이다 우리
compute all these crazy intermediates and it somehow magically works out to
이 모든 미친 중간체를 계산하고 어떻게 든 마술에 밖으로 작동
compute the output asymptotically faster than the naive method and you know from
순진한 방법보다 점근 적으로 빠른 출력을 계산하고 당신은 알고
him to call me know that matrix multiplication is this we can implement
그 날 행렬 곱셈이 우리가 구현할 수있는 것을 알고 호출
convolution as matrix multiplication to intuitively you might expect that these
행렬 곱셈 같은 회선은 직관적으로 이러한 것을 예상합니다
similar types of tricks might theoretically maybe be applicable to
트릭 비슷한 유형의 이론적 아마에 적용 할 수 있습니다
convolution and it turns out they are so there's this really cool paper that just
컨볼 루션 그것은 그들이 그렇게이 정말 멋진 용지가있을 수 있습니다 밝혀 그 단지
came out over the summer where these two guys worked out very explicitly that
이 두 사람이 아주 명시 적으로 밖으로 일 여름 동안 나왔다
something very special cases 43 by frequent allusions and it involves this
뭔가 아주 특별한 경우를 자주 암시 43 그것은이 포함됩니다
obviously I'm not going to go into details here but it's a similar flavor
분명 여기 세부 사항으로 이동하지 않을거야하지만 비슷한 맛이다
to stress and computing very clever intermediate
스트레스와 중간 아주 영리한 계산에
and Henry combining them to actually save a lot on the computation and these
헨리 실제로 계산과 이들에 많이 저장을 결합
guys are actually really really intense and they're not just mathematicians they
사람은 실제로 정말 강렬하고 그들은 단지 수학자하지 않은 그들
actually wrote also highly highly optimized CUDA kernels to compute these
실제로 또한 매우 높은이를 계산하기위한 CUDA 커널을 최적화 쓴
things and were able to speed up BGG by a factor of two so that's really really
두 배 BGG을 단축 할 수 있었다 물건 그래서 정말 정말
impressive so I think that these these type this type of truck might become
인상적인 그래서 나는이 이러한 유형의 트럭이 유형이 될 수 있다는 생각
pretty popular in the future but for the time being I think it's not very widely
인 미래하지만 시간이 꽤 인기가 나는 그것이 매우 광범위하지 생각
used but these numbers are crazy especially for small batch sizes they're
사용하지만이 숫자는 특히 그들이있어 작은 배치 크기에 미친
getting a six speed up on BGG that's that's really really impressive and I
그게 정말 인상적이고 I의의 BGG에 여섯 속도를 점점
think it's a really cool method the downside is that you kinda have to work
단점은 당신이 좀 일을해야한다는 것입니다 그것은 정말 멋진 방법이라고 생각
out these explicit special cases each different size of convolution but maybe
이러한 명시 적으로 특별한 경우 외부 회선 각각 다른 크기 그러나 아마
if we only care about three by three convolutions that's not such a big deal
우리는 3 × 3 회선에 대해 신경 경우 그는 큰 문제가 아니다
so the recap computing convolutions in practice is that the sort of the really
그래서 실제로 회선 컴퓨팅 정리해은 그 진짜의 종류
fast easy quick and dirty way to implement these things is in to call
이러한 것들을 구현하는 빠르고, 쉽고 신속하고 더러운 방법은 전화에서입니다
matrix multiplication is passed it does it's usually not too hard to implement
행렬 곱셈이 전달됩니다 그것을 구현하는 것이 너무 어렵지 않다 않습니다
these things so if for some reason you really need to implement competitions
이 것을 어떤 이유로 당신이 정말로 대회를 구현해야하는 경우 이렇게
yourself I'd really recommend into call activity is something that coming from
자신을 정말 통화 활동에 권 해드립니다은 오는 뭔가
signal processing you might think would be really cool and really useful but it
당신이 생각하는 신호 처리 정말 시원하고 정말 유용하지만 것
turns out that it's it does give speed ups but only for big filters so it's not
그것은하지 그래서는하지만 큰 필터의 속도 업을 주는가 있다고 밝혀
as useful as you might have hoped but there is hope because these fast
당신이 희망하지만 한 수만큼이 빠른 때문에 희망 유용있다
algorithms are really good
알고리즘은 정말 좋아
filters and there already exists code somewhere in the world to do it so
이미 세계 어딘가에 코드가 존재하고 필터는 그렇게 할 일
hopefully these these things will catch on and become more widely used so if
희망이 이러한 것들에 잡아 더 널리 그래서 만약 사용 될 것입니다
there's any questions about computing convolutions
계산 회선에 대해 질문이있다
ok so next we're gonna talk about some implementation details so first question
확인을 우리는 첫 번째 질문 그래서 일부 구현 세부 사항에 대한 거 이야기를 그렇게 옆에있어
how do you guys ever built your own computer
어떻게 너희들은 지금까지 자신의 컴퓨터를 구축 할
ok so you guys are prevented from this answer on this next slide so who can
확인 그래서 너희들은 너무 사람이 할 수있는이 다음 슬라이드에이 답변 방지 할 수있다
spot the CPU anyone on a point out
아웃 지점의 CPU 사람을 발견
the CPU is this little guy right so actually this this thing is actually a
CPU는이 작은 사람이 바로 그래서 실제로는이 일이 사실이다
lot of it is the cooler so the CPU itself is a little tiny part inside of
는 CPU 자체의 내부에 약간의 작은 부분이 그래서 그것의 많은 쿨러입니다
here a lot of this is actually the heatsink cooling the next spot the GPU
여기 많은 다음 스폿에게 GPU 냉각 방열판 실제로
yes it's the thing that says GeForce on and so this GPU is is for one thing it's
네, 그것은에 등이 GPU는 지포스를 말하는 것은 그것의 한 가지입니다입니다
it's much larger and the CPU so you might so it may be is is more powerful I
그것은 훨씬 더 큰 그리고 당신은 그래서 할 수 있습니다 있도록 CPU는 더 강력한 I하다
know but at least it's taking up more space in the case so that's that's kind
알고 있지만 그 종류의 그, 그래서 적어도이 경우에 더 많은 공간을 복용
of an indication that something exciting is happening so I'm another question and
흥미로운 일이 너무 일어나고 있다는 표시로 나는 또 다른 질문을하고 있는데
you gotta play video games
당신 돼 플레이 비디오 게임
ok then you probably have opinions about this so turns out a lot of people in
확인 후, 당신은 아마 그래서 사람들이 많이 밝혀 이에 대한 의견
machine learning and deep learning have really strong opinions too and most
기계 학습과 깊은 학습도 정말 강한 의견을 가지고 대부분의
people are on the side so Nvidia is actually much much more widely used then
사람들은 그래서 엔비디아 실제로는 훨씬 더 널리 후 사용 측면에 있습니다
AMD for you using GPUs and US and the reason is that
AMD는 당신이 GPU는 미국을 사용하는 이유는 것입니다
NVIDIA has really done a lot in the last couple of years to really dive into deep
NVIDIA는 정말 정말 깊이로 다이빙 지난 몇 년에 많은 일을하고있다
learning and make it a really core part of their focus so as a cool example of
정도의 멋진 예를 들어 학습과 자신의 초점이 정말 핵심 부분 확인
that last year at GTC which is an
입니다 GTC에서 작년
videos sort of yearly big gigantic conference for the announce new products
발표 새로운 제품에 대한 연간 큰 거대한 회의의 비디오 정렬
Jensen Hong who is the CEO of in video and actually also stanford alarm
비디오에서의 CEO 실제로 또한 스탠포드 경보입니다 젠슨 홍콩
introduced this latest and greatest amazing new GPU capitation acts like
이 최신 가장 놀라운 새로운 GPU의 인두세 행위 등 소개
their flagship thing and the benchmark he used to sell it was how fast the
자신의 주력 것은 그가 그것을 판매하는 데 사용되는 벤치 마크는 얼마나 빨리
country and Alex met so this was crazy
국가와 알렉스는 그렇게 만난이 미쳤다
this was a gigantic room with like hundreds and hundreds of people and
이 같은 수백 수백명의 사람들과 함께 거대한 방이었다
journalists and like this gigantic highly polished presentation and the CEO
이 거대한 높은 광택 프리젠 테이션 및 CEO 등 언론인과
of in video was talking about Alex net and convolutions and I thought that was
비디오에서 알렉스 그물 및 회선에 대해 얘기하고, 나는 그것이라고 생각했다
really exciting and it kind of shows you that Nvidia really cares a lot about
정말 흥분하고 가지 방법을 보여줍니다 엔비디아는 정말 많은 약을 걱정하는 것이
getting these things to work and they pushed a lot of their efforts into
이 일을 얻는 것은 일을하고 그들에 노력을 많이 밀어하기
getting into making it work so just to give you an idea a CPU as you probably
그렇게 그냥 작동 제작에 들어가는 것은 아마 같은 생각을 당신에게 CPU를 제공합니다
know is really good at fast sequential processing and they tend to have a small
빠른 순차 처리에 정말 좋은 알고 그들은 작은을 갖는 경향이
number of cores your laptop probably have like maybe between one and four
코어의 수는 노트북은 아마 어쩌면 사이에 하나 사처럼이
corners and big things on a server might have up to 16 quarters and these things
서버의 모서리와 큰 일 최대 4분의 16과 이런 일이있을 수 있습니다
are really good at computing things really really fast
컴퓨팅 물건 정말 정말 빨리에게 정말 좋은
and in sequence GPU is on the other hand tend to have many many many course for a
그리고 순서 GPU 반면에는 많은 많은 많은 과정을 갖는 경향
big guy like a tax it can have up to thousands of quarters but they tend each
세금 등 큰 사람은 분기 수천까지 가질 수 있지만 각 경향
core can do last May 10 2010 lower clock speed and be able to do less per
코어는 지난 2010년 5월 10일 낮은 클럭 속도를하고 당 더 적은을 할 수 있습니다
instruction cycle so these GPUs again we actually were originally developed for
이 GPU는 다시 우리가 실제로 처음으로 개발되었다 있도록 명령어 사이클
processing graphics graphics processing units so they're really good at doing
처리 그래픽 그래픽 처리 장치는 그래서 그들은 일에 정말 좋은거야
sort of highly paralyzed operations are you wanna do many many things in
일종의 고도의 마비 작업은 싶어 많은 많은 일을 할 수 있습니다
parallel independently and since they were originally designed for computer
독립적으로 평행하고 원래 컴퓨터를 위해 설계 되었기 때문에
graphics but since then they've sort of evolved as a more general computing
그래픽은 그러나 그 이후 그들은 종류의보다 일반적인 컴퓨팅으로 진화했습니다
platform so there are different frameworks that allow you to write
당신이 쓸 수 다른 프레임 워크가 플랫폼 있도록
generic code to run directly on the GPU so from Nvidia we have this framework
엔비디아에서 우리는이 프레임 워크를 그래서 일반적인 코드는 GPU에서 직접 실행하기
that lets you write a variant of seats actually write code that runs directly
그것은 당신이 실제로 직접 실행되는 코드를 작성 시트의 변형을 작성할 수 있습니다
on the GPU and there's a similar framework called OpenCL that works on
GPU에서와에 작동 오픈 CL이라는 비슷한 프레임 워크가있다
pretty much any any computational platform but I mean open standards are
거의 모든 컴퓨팅 플랫폼 어느 정도하지만 개방형 표준이되는 의미
nice and it's quite nice that OpenCL works everywhere but in practice open so
좋은 그것은 OpenCL을 사방에 작동하는지 아주 좋다하지만 실제로는 그렇게 열
that tends to be a lot more performance and how a little bit nicer library
즉, 더 많은 성능과 방법을 조금 더 멋진 도서관 경향이있다
support so at least four deep learning most people use could instead and if
지원 적어도 네 깊은 학습 대부분의 사람들이 사용할 수 있도록 할 수 대신하고있는 경우
you're interested in actually learning how to write G Piko G Piko yourself
실제로 G PIKO G PIKO를 직접 작성하는 방법을 학습에 관심
there's a really cool nasty course I would it's it's pretty cool have fun
나는 그것이 꽤 멋지다의 것 정말 멋진 불쾌한 과정이 재미 있어요
assignments all that lets you write code to run things on GPU although in
당신이 코드는 GPU에 일을 실행에 쓸 수 있습니다 할당 모두 있지만,
practice if all you want to do is train come nuts and do research and that sort
당신이 원하는 모든 경우 방법은 기차 너트를 와서 연구와 그와 같은 작업을 수행
of thing you end up usually not having to write any of this code yourself you
일의 당신은 일반적으로이 코드를 직접 당신이 중 하나를 작성하지 않아도 결국
just rely on external libraries
단지 외부 라이브러리에 의존
right so could I is like this this raw so cute and higher higher level library
바로 그렇게 할 수 나는이 너무 귀엽다이 원 이상 높은 수준의 도서관처럼
kind of like glass right so one thing that GPUs are really really good at is
종류의 유리 바로 그래서 한 가지 같은 GPU는에 정말 정말 좋은 것을
matrix multiplication so here's here's a benchmark I mean this is from Nvidia's
행렬 곱셈은 그래서 여기 여기 난이 엔비디아의에서 인 벤치 마크 뜻이야
website so it's a little bit biased but this is showing matrix multiplication
웹 사이트는 그래서 조금 편견이다 그러나 이것은 행렬 곱셈을 보이고있다
time as a function of matrix eyes on a pretty beefy CPU this is a 12 corps guy
이 꽤 살이 찐 CPU에 매트릭스 눈의 함수로 시간은 12 군단의 사람입니다
that would live in a server that's like quite a quite a healthy CPU and this is
그것은 아주 아주 건강한 CPU처럼 서버에 살고있는 것이입니다
running the same date science matrix multiply on a test like a 40 which is a
를 인 40 같은 시험에서 곱셈 같은 날짜 과학 행렬을 실행
pretty beefy GPU and it's much faster I mean that's no big surprise right and
꽤 살이 찐 GPU 그것은 훨씬 더 빨리 내가​​ 그 더 큰 놀라움 오른쪽 없습니다 의미이고
GPUs are also really gotta convolutions so as you mentioned and video has a
당신이 언급 한 비디오는이되도록 GPU는 또한 정말 꼭 회선입니다
library called today announced that is specifically optimized optimist CUDA
오늘 호출 라이브러리는 특별히 최적화 된 낙관주의 CUDA를 발표했다
kernels for convolution so compared to CPU I mean it's it's WAY faster and this
회선에 대한 커널 그래서 내 말은 CPU에 비해​​ 그것은 WAY 빨리이의의
is actually comparing him to call contributions from campaign with the
실제로 그를 비교하는 것은 함께 캠페인의 기여를 호출
crew tienen convolutions I think these graphs are actually from the first
승무원 티에 넨 회선 나는이 그래프는 처음부터 실제로 생각
version of CNN version for just came out a few weeks ago and but this is the only
CNN 버전의 버전은 단지 몇 주 전에 나와서 그러나 이것은 단지입니다
version where they actually had a CPU benchmark since then the benchmark civil
실제로 다음 벤치 마크 토목 때문에 CPU 벤치 마크했다 버전
me been against previous versions so it's got a lot faster since then since
더 빨리 그 이후부터 많이있어, 그래서 나 이전 버전에 대해되었습니다
here but the way this witness fits and is that something like two blasts or to
여기에 있지만 증거가 맞는 방법은 두 개의 폭발 같은 또는 뭔가
DNN is a C library so it provides functions and see that just sort of
이 기능을 제공하고 단지 종류의 것을 볼 수 있도록 DNN은 C 라이브러리입니다
abstract away the GPU as a C library so if you have a tensor sort of in in
C 라이브러리와 GPU 멀리 추상 그래서 당신은 일종의에서의 텐서이있는 경우
memory and see you can just pass a pointer to the Korean library and it'll
메모리와 방금 한국 라이브러리에 대한 포인터를 전달할 수 있습니다보고는거야
return the conf little running on GPU maybe asynchronously and return the
conf의 작은 아마 비동기 적으로 GPU에서 실행 돌아가서를 반환
result so frameworks like cafe and torch all have now integrated the Q tienen
결과 카페와 토치와 같은 프레임 워크 있도록 모든 이제 Q의 티에 넨을 통합 한
stuff into their own frameworks you can utilize these efficient solutions in any
물건을 자신의 프레임 워크에 당신은 어떤에서 이러한 효율적인 솔루션을 활용할 수
of these frameworks know but the problem is that even when once we have these
이 프레임 워크는 알고 있지만, 문제는 그 우리는이를 일단 경우에도
really powerful GPUs training big models is still kind
정말 큰 모델을 훈련 강력한 GPU는 종류 여전히
slow so VG nett was famously train for something like two to three weeks on for
VG 정가가에 2 ~ 3 주 같은 훈련을 유명하게되었다 그래서 천천히
Titan what was a Titan black sandals aren't cheap and it was actually a
타이탄 무엇 타이탄 블랙 샌들은 싸지 않다이었고, 그것은 실제로이었다
recommendation of ResNet recently there's a really cool right up this
ResNet의 추천은 최근이 최대 정말 멋진 바로 거기
really cool blog post describing it here and they actually retrained the ResNet
정말 멋진 블로그 게시물 여기를 설명하고 실제로 ResNet을 재교육
hundred and one layer model and it also took about two weeks to train on for
백 한 레이어 모델과 또한 동안 훈련을 2 주 정도 걸렸다
GPUs so that's not good and the one way that people the way that the easy way to
그 좋지 않다, 그래서 GPU를하고 한 방향으로 그 사람들이 길을 쉬운 방법으로 그
split up training across multiple GPUs is just to split your money back across
당신의 돈을 돌려 걸쳐 분할되어 여러 GPU에 걸쳐 교육을 분할
the GPUs so normally you might have you especially for someone like BGG it takes
당신이 특히 BGG 같은 사람을 위해 당신이 수있는 GPU를 정상적으로 있도록 소요
a lot of memory so you can't compete with very large me batch sizes on a
많은 메모리 그래서 당신은 매우 큰 나 배치 크기와 경쟁 할 수
single GPU so what you'll do you have any batch of images may be a 6:00 128 or
단일 GPU 당신은 당신이 할 거 야 그래서 어떤 이미지의 배치가 될 수있는 6 128
something like that
그런 일
than any match into four equal chunks each GPU compute a forward and backward
네 개의 동일한 조각으로 어떤 경기보다 각각의 GPU는 순방향 및 역방향을 계산
pass for that many batch in your compute pramit gradients on the weights while
가중치 반면에 계산 pramit 구배에 많은 배치에 대해 통과
some of those weights inside your some of those weights after all for GPU
GPU에 대한 후 모든 무게 당신의 일부 내부에 그 무게의 일부
Spanish and make an update your model so this is a really simple way that people
스페인어와이 정말 간단한 방법 즉 있도록 업데이 트 모델을 만드는 사람들
tend to implement distribution on GPUs yeah yeah
그래 GPU에서 분포를 구현하는 경향이
yeah yeah so that's why they claim that they can automate this process and
그들은이 과정을 자동화 할 수 있다고 주장 왜 그래 그래서 그건 및
really really efficiently distribute it which is really exciting I think but I
정말 정말 효율적으로 내가 생각하는 정말 흥분되는에게 배포하지만
haven't played much myself and also at least in torch there's a data parallel
적어도 토치도 자신을 많이 연주되지 않은 데이터 병렬있다
there that you can just drop in and use that all sort of automatically do with
당신이 그냥 드롭과는 자동으로 모든 종류의 사용할 수있는
this type of parallelism very easily
병렬 이런 종류의 아주 쉽게
a slightly more complex idea for multi GPU training actually comes from Alex
멀티 GPU 훈련을위한 약간 더 복잡한 아이디어는 실제로 알렉스에서 온다
Alex not fame
알렉스되지 명성
guess that's kind of cool kind of a funny title but the idea but the idea is
그 재미있는 제목의 멋진 가지 종류하지만 생각 생각하지만, 생각은
that we want to actually do data parallelism on the lower layers so on
우리는 실제로 하위 계층에 등을 데이터 병렬 처리를 수행하도록
the lower layers will take our image many batch split up across two GPUs and
우리의 이미지를 여러 배치를 취할 것 하위 계층은 두 개의 GPU를 통해 분할 및
eat and GPU one will compute the convolutions for the first part first
먹고 GPU 하나는 먼저 첫 번째 부분에 대해 컨볼 루션을 계산하는 것
part of the many batch and just released just this comp convolution part will be
많은 배치의 일부 단지 발표 그냥 빌려 컨볼 루션 부분이 될 것입니다
distributed equally across the GPUs but once you get to the fully connected
GPU에 걸쳐 균등하게 분포하지만 당신이 일단 완전 연결
layers
층
he found it's actually more efficient if you are just really big matrix
그는 당신이 정말 큰 매트릭스 경우 실제로 더 효율적 발견
multiplies then it's more efficient actually have the GPS work together to
승산은 실제로 서로에 GPS 작업이 더 효율적
compute this matrix multiply this is kind of a cool track it's not very
매우 아니다이 행렬이 멋진 트랙의 종류 곱 계산
commonly used but I thought it's it's fun to mention another idea from Google
일반적으로 사용하지만 그것이 구글에서 다른 생각을 언급하는 재미의 생각
is before it before there was tenser flow they had this thing called
tenser 흐름이되기 전에 그들이이 일이라고했다 전에이다
disbelief which was their their previous system which was entirely CPU based
전체 CPU 기반이었다 자신의 이전 시스템이었다 불신
which from the benchmarks a few slides ago you can imagine was going to be
몇 슬라이드 전에 벤치 마크에서 당신이 될 줄 상상도 할 수있는
really slow but actually the first version of Google Matt was all trained
정말 느리지 만 실제로 구글 매트의 첫 번째 버전은 모든 훈련을했다
in disbelief on CPU so they actually so they had to do massive amounts of
CPU에 대한 불신 때문에 실제로 그래서 그들은 엄청난 양의 작업을 수행했다
distribution on CPU to get these things to train so here there's this cool paper
CPU에 분포는이 멋진 종이 거기에 이런 일이 그래서 여기에 훈련을받을
from jap teen a couple years ago that describes this and a lot more detail but
이 설명 몇 년 전 JAP 청소년과 더 많은 세부 사항 만에서
you use data parallelism or you have each machine have an independent copy of
당신은 데이터 병렬 처리를 사용하거나 각 시스템이 독립적 인 복사본이
the model and each machine as computing forward and backward on patches of data
데이터의 패치에 모델과 앞으로 컴퓨팅 각 기계 및 이전 버전
but now i text you actually have this parameters server that's storing the
하지만 지금은 당신이 실제로 저장있어이 매개 변수 서버가 텍스트
parameters of the model and these independent workers are making
모델의 매개 변수와 이러한 독립적 인 노동자 만들고있다
communication with the parameters server to make updates on the model and they
파라미터 서버와의 통신 모델을 업데이트 할 수 있으며하도록
contrast this with model parallelism which is where you type 1
당신이 1을 입력 어디 모델 병렬로이 대조
model and you have different different workers computing different parts of the
모델 당신은의 다른 부분을 계산하는 다른 다른 노동자
model so and in disbelief they really did a really good job
그래서 모델과 불신에 그들은 정말 정말 좋은 일을했다
optimizing this to work really well across many many CPUs and many many
이 많은 많은 CPU와 많은 많은 걸쳐 정말 잘 작동하도록 최적화
machines but now they have cancer flow which hopefully should do these things
기계는하지만 지금은 희망이 일을해야 암의 흐름이
more automatically and once you're doing these these these updates there's this
더 자동으로 당신이 이러한 업데이트를하고있어 일단이있다
idea between asynchronous STD and synchronous STD so synchronous STD is
비동기 STD 및 동기 STD 사이의 생각은 그래서 동기 STD입니다
one of the things like the naive thing you might expect you have any batch you
순진한 것 같은 것들 중 하나는 당신이 어떤 배치를 예상하면
split up across multiple workers each worker does forward and backward
각 노동자는 다수의 근로자에​​ 걸쳐 전후 않습니다 분할
computes gradients when you add up all the gradients and make a single model
당신은 모든 그라디언트를 추가하고 단일 모델을 그라데이션을 계산
updates this will this will sort of exactly simulate
업데이트이이 정확하게의 정렬 시뮬레이션 할 것
just computing but many batch on a larger machine but it could be kind of
그냥 계산하지만 더 큰 기계에 많은 배치하지만 종류의 수
slow since you to synchronize across machines this tends to be too much of a
당신이 기계를 통해 동기화 할 수 있기 때문에 속도가 느린 이것은 너무 많은 경향이있다
big deal when you're working with multiple GPUs on a single note but once
단일 노트에 여러 GPU를 작업 만 한 번하고 큰 문제
you're distributed across many many CPUs that district that I'm synchronization
당신은 많은 많은 CPU를 통해 내가 동기있어 그 지역을 분산하고
can actually be quite expensive so instead at least they also have this
사실은 꽤 비쌀 수 있으므로 대신 적어도 그들은이있다
concept of asynchronous STD where each model is just sort of making updates to
각 모델은 단지 종류의 제조 업데이트 인 비동기 STD의 개념
the to its own copy of the parameters and those have some notion of an
매개 변수의 복사본에 그는 몇 가지 개념이
eventual consistency where they sometimes periodically synchronize with
그들은 때로는 주기적으로 동기화 최종 일관성
each other and it's seems really complicated and hard to debug but they
서로 그것의 디버그하지만 정말 복잡하고 어려운 것 같다
got it to work so that's that's pretty cool and one of the really cool pictures
그렇게 작동하려면 그것은 정말 멋진 그림 중 하나가 꽤 멋진이고있어
so these two figures are both in the tensor flow paper and one of the
그래서이 두 숫자는 텐서 흐름 종이 모두이며 하나
pictures of tensor flow is that it should really make this type of
텐서 흐름의 이미지는 실제로 이러한 유형해야한다는 것이다
distribution much more transparent to the user that if you do happen to have
당신이 일어날 경우 그 사용자에게 훨씬 더 투명 유통
access to a big cluster of GPUs and CPUs and whatnot tenser flow should
의 GPU와 CPU를 큰 클러스터에 액세스하고 이것 저것 tenser 흐름해야
automatically be able to figure out the best way to do these kinds of
자동으로 이러한 종류의 할 수있는 최선의 방법을 알아낼 수
distributions combining data and model parallelism and just do it all for you
데이터 및 모델의 병렬 처리와 결합 분포는 당신을 위해 모든 것을 할
so that's that's really cool and I think that's that's the really exciting part
즉 그것은 정말 멋진이고, 그래서 나는 그게 정말 흥미로운 부분이라고 생각
about 1000 any any questions about the stupid training yeah
바보 훈련 약 1000 어떤 질문이 그래
and CN TK I haven't even taken a look at it yet
및 CN TK 나는 아직 그것을 살펴 촬영하지 않은
ok so next time there's a couple bottlenecks you should be aware of in
확인 그래서 다음 번에 ​​몇 병목 현상은 당신이 알고 있어야 거기
practice so expect like usually when you're training these things like this
연습은 그래서 일반적으로이 같은이 일을 훈련 할 때처럼 기대
distributed stuff is nice and great but you can actually go a long way with just
분산 물건 좋은 큰하지만 당신은 실제로 단지와 함께 먼 길을 갈 수 있습니다
a single GPU on a single machine and there there's a lot of bottlenecks that
하나의 단일 시스템에 GPU 및 병목 현상이 많이있다 그
can get in the way one is the communication between the CPU and GPU
그런데 하나 얻을 수 것은 GPU와 CPU 사이의 통신이며
actually and a lot of cases especially when the data is small the most
실제로 그리고 많은 경우, 데이터는 가장 작고, 특히
expensive part of the pipeline is copying the data onto the GPU and then
파이프 라인의 고가의 제품은 GPU에 다음의 데이터를 복사하는
copy it back once you get things under the GPU you can do
당신은 GPU에서 일을 일단 당신이 할 수있는 다시 복사
computation really really fast and efficiently but the copying is the
계산 정말 정말 빠르고 효율적으로하지만 복사는이다
really slow part so 11 idea as you want to make sure to avoid the memory copy
정말 느린 부분은 메모리 복사를 방지 할 수 있는지 확인하려면로 11 아이디어 그래서
like one thing that sometimes you see you all at each layer of the network is
같은 때때로 네트워크의 각 계층에서 모두 표시 한 것입니다
copying back and forth from CPU GPU and I'll be really inefficient and slow
CPU에 GPU에서 앞뒤로 복사하고 정말 비효율적이고 속도가 느려질 수 있습니다
everything down so ideally you want the whole forward and backward pass to run
그래서 이상적으로 모든 것을 아래로 실행하기 위해 앞으로 전체와 후방 패스를 할
on a GPU at once
GPU에에 한 번
another thing you'll sometimes see is multithreaded approach where you'll have
당신이 볼 수있는 곳 가끔 볼 수 있습니다 또 다른 한가지는 접근 방식을 다중 스레드
a CPU thread that is prefetching data many memory in one thread in the
에 하나의 스레드에서 데이터 많은 메모리를 프리 페치 된 CPU 스레드
background
배경
possibly also appointed augmentations online and then this this background CPU
아마도 온라인 보강을 임명하고이이 배경 CPU
throughout will be sort of preparing me batches and possibly also shipping them
전역 종류의를 발송도 가능 나에게 배치를 준비 할 것
over to GPU you can kind of coordinate this loading of data and computing
이상 GPU에 당신은 종류의 데이터와 컴퓨팅이로드를 조정할 수 있습니다
preprocessing and shipping memory shipping
전처리 및 배송 메모리 배송
many batch data to the GPU and actually doing the computations and actually you
많은 배치 데이터를 GPU에 실제로 계산을하고 실제로
can get pretty involved with some courting I'll be all these things in a
아주 약간의 구애에 참여할 수 난의 모든 것을 알 수있을 것입니다
multithreaded way and I can give you some good speedups so cafe in particular
멀티 스레드 방식으로 나는 특히 카페 있도록 당신에게 좋은 속도 향상을 제공 할 수 있습니다
I think already implements this prefetching date on there for certain
나는 이미 생각 특정 거기에이 프리 페치 날짜를 구현
types of data storages and other frameworks you just have to roll your
데이터 스토리지 및 기타 프레임 워크의 유형 당신은 롤이 당신의
own another problem is that the CPU disk model Mac so these these things are kind
또 다른 문제는 CPU 디스크 모델 Mac 그래서이 이러한 일들이 친절이다 소유
of slow they're cheap and they're big but they actually are not the best so so
느린 그들은 저렴하고있어 그들은 큰이야하지만 그들은 실제로 그렇게 그렇게 가장하지 않습니다
these are hard disks that now the solid state drives are much more common
이제 이러한 고체 드라이브는 훨씬 더 일반적인 하드 디스크이다
but the problem is a solid state drives are you know smaller and more expensive
그러나 문제는 고체 상태 드라이브는 더 작고 비용이 알고있는 것이다
but they're a lot faster so they get used a lot in practice so what's really
하지만 그들은 실제로 많이 익숙해 빨리 너무 많이 그래서 무슨 일이 정말이야
although one 1 common feature to both hard disks and solid-state drives as
비록 하드 디스크 및 고체 상태 드라이브와 같은 양으로 하나 하나 공통점
they work best when you're reading data sequentially off the desk so a lot of
당신이 그렇게 책상을 많이 떨어져 데이​​터를 순차적으로 읽고있는 때 가장 잘 작동
times what you're right so one thing that would be really bad for example is
예는 정말 나쁜 것 당신이 바로 그렇게 한 일을하는지 번
to have a big folder full of JPEG images because now each of these images could
이제 이러한 이미지를 각각 때문에 JPEG 이미지의 전체 큰 폴더를해야합니다 수
be located in different parts on the desk so it could be really up to a
그것까지 정말이 될 수 있도록 책상에 다른 부분에 위치 할
random seek to read any individual JPEG image and now also once you read the
임의의 사용자가 읽어도 일단 지금은 개별 JPEG 이미지를 읽어 추구하고
JPEG you have to decompress it into pixels that's quite inefficient so what
JPEG는 그렇게 무엇을 매우 비효율적 그 픽셀에 압축을 해제해야
you'll see a lot of times in practice is that you'll actually preprocessor data
당신은 연습에 많은 시간이 표시됩니다 당신거야 실제로 처리기 데이터가
by decompressing it and just riding out the raw pixels entire data sat in one
그것을 압축 해제 단지 전체 데이터를 하나에 앉아 원시 픽셀을 타고
giant contiguous files to desk so that that takes a lot of disk space but we do
그래서 책상에 거대한 연속 파일이 디스크 공간을 많이 걸리지 만 우리가 할
it anyway because it's all for the good of a calmness right so this is kinda so
그것은 어쨌든 그것은 평온의 좋은 모든 때문에 바로 그래서 이것은 좀 너무하다
in cafe we do this with a coupled with like a level d be is one commonly used
카페에서 우리가 할 레벨 D 등을 결합하여이 작업을 수행하는 것은 일반적으로 사용되는 하나입니다
format I've also used I also use html5 files a lot for us but the idea is that
형식은 또한 나 또한 HTML5를 사용하는 사용하는 우리를 위해 많은 파일하지만 아이디어는 것입니다했습니다
you want to just get your data all sequentially on desk and already turned
당신은 모든 순차적으로 책상에 이미 설정 데이터 싶어
into pixels Senate training when you're training you can store all your data in
픽셀 상원 훈련에 당신은 당신이 모든 데이터를 저장할 수있는 훈련 할 때
memory you have to read off desk when you wanna make that read as fast as
메모리 당신은 당신이 그 빠른 속도로 읽을 만들고 싶어 할 때 책상을 읽을 필요
possible and again with clever amounts of prefetching and multi-threaded stuff
프리 페의 영리한 금액과 멀티 스레드 물건을 다시 가능하고
you might have you might have won prized pitching a top desk while other
당신은 당신이 원 다른 동안 최고 책상 투구 소중히 수도있을 수 있습니다
competition is happening in the background
경쟁은 백그라운드에서 일어나는
another thing to keep in mind is GPU memory bottlenecks so GPUs big ones have
GPU가 큰 사람은 그래서 기억해야 할 또 다른 점은 GPU 메모리 병목 현상입니다
big ones have a lot of memory but not that much so the biggest GPUs you can
큰 사람은 많은 메모리를 가지고 있지만 그 정도의 가장 큰 GPU는 그래서 당신은 할 수 있습니다
buy right now that I tax and the key forty have 12 gigs of memory and that's
지금 내가 세금 것을 구입하고 키 마흔 메모리 12 기가를 가지고 그건
pretty much as big as you're going to get right now
당신이 지금받을거야으로 큰로서 꽤 많은
NextGen should be bigger but you can actually bump up against this limit
NextGen 더 큰해야하지만 실제로는이 제한에 반대 충돌 할 수 있습니다
without too much trouble especially if you're training something like a BG or
당신은 BG 또는 같은 것을 훈련하고 특히 너무 많은 문제없이
if you're having recurrent networks were very very very very long time stops it's
당신이 발생하는 경우 재발 네트워크는 매우 매우 매우 매우 긴 시간이 그것의 중지했다
actually not too hard to bump up against this memory limit that's something you
실제로 뭔가가있어이 메모리 제한에 반대 충돌하지 너무 열심히
need to keep
유지해야
mind when you're training these things and some of these planes about you know
당신이 알고에 대해 당신이이 비행기의 일부를이 일을 훈련하고있을 때 마음
these efficient convolutions and cleverly creating architectures actually
이러한 효율적인 회선 실제로 영리하게 만드는 구조
helps with this memory as well if you can have a bigger more powerful model
당신이 더 큰 더 강력한 모델을 가지고 할 수있는 경우뿐만 아니라이 메모리에 도움
with smaller amounts of with don't use less memory than you'll be able to train
와 적은 양의 메모리를 적게 사용하지 않는 당신은 훈련 할 수 있습니다보다
things faster and use bigger matches and everything is good and even just just a
일이 더 빠르고 더 큰 일치를 사용하고 모든 것이 좋고, 다만 단지
sense of scale Alex Knight is pretty small compared to a lot of the models
규모 알렉스 기사의 의미는 모델의 많은에 비해 매우 작다
that are state of the art now but Alex net with a 256 back sides already takes
이미 소요 256 다시 양쪽 이제 최첨단하지만 알렉스 그물이 있습니다
about 3 gigabytes GB memory so once you have to these bigger networks it's
대한 3기가바이트 GB 메모리 당신은 그것의이 더 큰 네트워크가 한 번 있도록
actually not too hard to bump up against the 12 Dec limits so another thing we
실제로 그래서 다른 일이 12 월 12 한계에 부딪하지 너무 열심히 우리
should talk about is floating point precision so when I'm writing code a lot
나는 많은 코드를 작성하고있을 때 너무 소수점 정밀도를 떠 대해 이야기한다
of times I like to imagine that you know these things are just real numbers and
시간의 나는 당신이 이러한 일들이 그냥 실수 알고 상상하기 좋아하고
they just work but in practice that's not true and you need to think about
그들은 단지 작동하지만 실제로 그것은 사실이 아니에요 당신은 생각해야
things like how many bits of floating-point are using so most types
부동 소수점의 얼마나 많은 비트 같은 것들 때문에 대부분의 유형을 사용하는
are a lot of types of numeric code that you might write sort of is with a double
당신이 일종의 작성할 수 있습니다 숫자 코드의 유형이 많이 이중으로되어 있습니다
precision by default this is using 64 bits and a lot of also wrote more
또한 작성의 기본이에 의해 정밀 64 비트를 많이 사용하고 더
commonly used for deep learning is this idea of single precision so this is only
이것은 단지 그래서 일반적으로 깊은 학습에 사용되는 단일 정밀도의이 아이디어는
32 bets so the idea is that if each number takes fewer bets then you can
32 내기 때문에 아이디어는 각 번호는 다음 적은 베팅 걸리는 경우 당신이 할 수있는 그
store more of those numbers within the same amount of memory so that's good and
그 좋은, 그래서 같은 양의 메모리 내에서 그 숫자를 더 저장하고
also with fewer bets you need less computes operate on those numbers that's
또한 적은 베팅으로 당신은 더 적은 계산하여이야 그 숫자에서 작동해야
also good so in general we would like to have smaller data types because they're
또한 우리는 그들이이기 때문에 작은 데이터 유형이 좋은 싶습니다 일반적 있도록
faster to compute and the useless memory and as a as a case study this was
빠른 계산하고 불필요한 메모리와 케이스 등의 연구로이 있었다
actually even an issue on homework so you may have noticed that and the
실제로 숙제에 심지어 문제는 그과를 눈치 챘을 수 있도록
default data type is this
기본 데이터 타입이있다
64 bit double precision but for all of these models that we provided you on
64 비트 배정 밀도하지만 우리가 당신을 제공하는이 모델의 모든
homework we had this cast or 32 bit floating point number and you can
숙제 우리는이 캐스트 또는 32 비트 부동 소수점 숫자를 가지고 있었고, 당신은 할 수
actually go back on the homework and try switching between these two and you'll
실제로 숙제에 돌아가서이 두 당신은거야 사이를 전환 시도
see that switching to the 32 bit actually gives you some decent some
32 비트로 전환하는 것은 실제로 당신에게 몇 가지 괜찮은 몇 가지를 제공합니다 볼
decent speed ups so bad and the obvious question is that if 32 bets are better
괜찮은 속도 업 그렇게 나쁜 명백한 문제는 그 32 베팅이 더 나은 경우
than 64 bet spend maybe we can use less than
64 내기 아마 지출보다 우리는 이하를 사용할 수 있습니다
so there's this right
그래서이 권리가있다
16 bets but it was ordered to do these great ok so in addition to 32 bit
16 베팅은 있지만 32 비트뿐만 아니라, 그래서이 큰 확인을 수행하도록 명령했다
floating point there's also a standard for 16 bit floating point which is
부동 소수점 16 비트 부동 소수점에 대한 표준도있다
sometimes called the half precision and actually recent versions of cunanan do
때로는 반 정밀도와 cunanan 실제로 최신 버전이 할라고
support computing things in a position that's cool and actually there there are
멋진 실제로 거기에있는 위치에서 지원 컴퓨팅 것들
some other other existing implementations from a company called
라는 회사에서 다른 기존의 구현
their bana who also has these sixteen-bit implementations so these are
이러한 그래서이 여섯 비트 구현되는이 자신의 바나
the fastest convolutions out there right now so these there's this nice get
이 좋은 GET있다이 때문에 지금 거기에 가장 빠른 회선
hungry poll that has different kinds of comment benchmarks for different types
다른 유형의 주석 벤치 마크의 종류가 배고픈 설문 조사
of convolutions and frameworks and everything and pretty much everything
회선 및 프레임 워크 및 모든과 거의 모든의
winning all these benchmarks right now are these 16 bit floating point
우승이 모든 벤치 마크 지금이 16 비트 부동 소수점입니다
operations from Nirvana which is not surprising right because I can you have
난 당신이 가질 수 있기 때문에 놀라운 일이 옳지 않다 너바나에서 작업
your bets so it's faster to compete but right now there's actually not yet
베팅 더 빨리, 그래서 경쟁하지만 지금 아직 사실이 아니다합니다
framework support in things like cafe or torch for utilizing the sixteen-bit
열 여섯 비트를 이용하기위한 카페 또는 토치 같은 것들에 프레임 워크 지원
computation but it should be coming very soon but the problem is that even if we
계산하지만 곧 다가오는되어야하지만, 문제는 우리하더라도
can compute it's it's it's pretty obvious that if you have 16 but numbers
계산할 수 그것은 꽤 분명이야이야 당신은 16 만 번호가있는 경우
you can compete with them very fast but once you get to 16 better than you might
당신은 매우 빠른 그들과 경쟁하지만, 일단 (16)이 수도보다 더 얻을 수 있습니다
actually be worried about numeric precision because two of the sixteen is
열 여섯의 두 가지이기 때문에 실제로 숫자 정밀도에 대한 걱정
not that big of a number anymore it's actually not too many real numbers you
다수의 큰되지는 더 이상 실제로 너무 많은 실수 당신입니다
can even represent so there is this paper from a couple years ago that did
심지어 표현 그래서 몇 년 전에했던 것과이 논문이있다 할 수 있습니다
some experiments low precision floating point and they found that actually just
일부 실험 낮은 정밀도 부동 소수점 그들은 발견 실제로 단지
using the experiment they actually use a fixed with a floating-point
실험을 사용하여 그들이 실제로는 부동 소수점 고정 사용
implementation and they found that actually with these very with with this
구현 및 그들이 발견 사실이 매우이와
sort of naive implementation of oslo of these low precision methods the networks
이러한 낮은 정밀 방법 네트워크의 오슬로의 순진 구현의 종류
had a hard time converging probably due to these low precision Americare numeric
때문에이 낮은 정밀 Americare의 숫자에 아마 수렴 힘든 시간을했다
issues that kind of accumulate over multiple rounds of multiplication and
종류의 곱셈의 여러 라운드를 통해 축적 문제와
whatnot but they found a simple trick was actually this idea of stochastic
이것 저것 그러나 그들은 간단한 트릭이 실제로 확률이 아이디어 발견
rounding so some of their multiplications would so all their
자신의 곱셈의 일부는 그렇게 것 때문에 모든 라운딩 자신의
parameters
매개 변수
activations are stored in 16 bet but when they perform a multiplication they
정품 인증은 16 건에 저장되지만, 그들은 곱셈 그들은을 수행 할 때
up converts to a slightly higher precision floating-point value and then
가입은 약간 높은 정밀도 부동 소수점 값으로 변환
they still cast a round that back down to a lower position and actually doing
그들은 여전히​​ 낮은 위치까지 다시 라운드를 캐스팅하고 실제로 일을
that rounding in a stochastic way that is not rounding to the nearest number
그 가장 가까운 숫자로 반올림되지 않은 확률 적 방법으로 반올림
but probabilistically rounding two different numbers that depending on how
그러나 확률 적 방식에 따라 서로 다른 번호를 라운딩
close you are
당신이 닫습니다
tends to work better and practice so they found that for example when you're
더 나은 일을하고 그렇게 연습을하는 경향이 그들은 예를 들어 당신이있을 때 발견
using these were sixteen-bit fixed numbers with two beds for integers and
여섯 비트 고정 번호는 정수 두 개의 침대가 있었다 이러한 사용
stand between 12 and 14 this for the floating point for the for the
에 대한에 대한 부동 소수점 12, 14이 사이 서
fractional part that when you use this idea of always rounding to the nearest
당신의이 아이디어를 사용할 때 항상 가장 가까운 반올림 것을 소수 부분
number these networks and to diverge but when you use these stochastic grounding
수 이러한 네트워크 및 분기 만하는 이러한 확률 접지를 사용하는 경우
techniques that you can actually get these networks to converge quite nicely
실제로 이러한 네트워크는 아주 잘 수렴 얻을 수있는 기술
even with these very low precision floating-point technique low precision
심지어이 매우 낮은 밀도 부동 소수점 기술 낮은 정밀도
floating-point numbers but you might want to ask will sixteen-bit is great
부동 소수점 수 있지만 16 개의 비트가됩니다 대단한 문의 할 수 있습니다
but can we go even lower than that there was another paper in 2015 that got down
그러나 우리는 아래로있어 2015 년 다른 용지가보다하는 것이 더 낮은 갈 수 있습니다
to 10 and 12 bets so here that I mean from the previous paper we already had
10 그래서 여기에 우리가 이미 가지고 있던 이전의 논문에서 의미하는 것으로 12 베팅
this intuition that maybe when you're using very low precision floating-point
이 직관 어쩌면 당신은 매우 낮은 정밀도를 사용하는 부동 소수점
numbers you actually need to use more precision in some parts of the network
숫자는 실제로 네트워크의 일부 지역에서 더 정밀도를 사용할 필요가
and lower precision in other parts of the network so in this paper they were
네트워크의 다른 부분에서 낮은 정밀이 논문에서 그들은했다 그래서
able to get away with using story in the activations in 10 bit 10 bit values and
(10)의 활성화에 이야기를 사용하여 멀리 얻을 수 10 비트 값을 비트 및
stand doing computing gradients using 12 bets and they've got this to work which
12 베팅을 사용하여 컴퓨팅 그라데이션을하고 서서 그들은이 일을 가지고있는
is pretty amazing but anyone think that that's the limit can we go further
꽤 훌륭하지만 사람이 그 한계는 우리가 더 갈 수 있다고 생각
yes
예
there was actually a paper just last week so this is actually from the same
이 같은에서 실제로 있도록 용지는 지난 주에 실제로 있었다
author as the previous paper and this is crazy I was I was amazed about this and
이전의 종이로 제작이는 내가 이것에 대해 놀랐다했다 미친이며,
hear the idea is that all activations and weights of a network use only one
개념 네트워크의 모든 활성화 및 가중치 하나만​​을 사용하는 것이 듣는
bet either one or negative one that's pretty fast to compute now you don't
지금은 그렇지 계산하기 위해 꽤 빨리 둘 중 하나 또는 음을 내기
even really have to do multiplication you can just do like why is explored and
심지어 정말 그냥 탐험 왜 같이 할 수 곱셈을해야하고
multiply those that's pretty cool but the trick is that on the forward pass
꽤 멋진 것들을 곱하지만 트릭은 앞으로 패스를 그이다
all of the gradients and activations are either one or minus one so it's super
이 슈퍼 그래서 기울기 및 정품 인증 모두가 하나 또는 마이너스 하나
stuff four passes super super fast and efficient but now on a backward pass
슈퍼 슈퍼 신속하고 효율적인하지만 지금은 뒤로 패스에 물건 4 패스
they actually compute gradients using higher precision and then these higher
그들은 실제로 높은 정밀도와 다음이 이상을 사용하여 그라데이션을 계산
precision gradients are used to actually make updates to these single bit
정밀 그라디언트 실제로 이러한 단일 비트에 대한 업데이트를 확인하는 데 사용됩니다
parameters so it's it's it's actually really cool paper and I'd encourage you
그것은 그래서 매개 변수는 실제로 정말 멋진 종이 그리고 내가 당신을 격려 것입니다
to check it out but the pitch is that may be a training time you can afford to
그것을 확인하지만 피치는 그 당신이 감당할 수있는 훈련 시간이 될 수있다합니다
use maybe more floating point precision but then a test time do you want your
어쩌면 부동 소수점 정밀도를 사용하지만 시험 시간은 당신이 원하는 마십시오
network to be super super fast and all binary so I think this is a really
나는 이것이 정말 생각 때문에 네트워크 슈퍼 슈퍼 빠른 모든 이진 될 수 있습니다
really cool idea that I mean it the paper just came out two weeks ago so I
나는 그것을 용지 뜻 정말 멋진 아이디어는 내가 2 주 전에 나온
don't know but I think it's a pretty cool thing so the recap from
알고하지만 난 그것을에서 정리 해보 그래서 정말 멋진 일이 생각하지 않습니다
implementation details
구현 세부 사항
is that overall GPUs are much much faster than CPUs sometimes people use
전체 GPU는 CPU가 때때로 사람들이 사용보다 훨씬 더 빠르게 있다는 것입니다
distributed training distributing over multiple GPUs in one system is pretty
하나의 시스템에서 여러 GPU에 걸쳐 배포 배포 훈련은 예쁜
common if your Google and using tensor flow then distributing over multiple
일반 사용자의 구글과 사용 텐서 여러를 통해 배포 한 후 흐르는 경우
nodes is maybe more common be aware of the potential bottlenecks between the
노드는 어쩌면 더 일반적인 사이의 잠재적 인 병목을 알고 있어야한다
CPU and GPU between the GPU in the desk and between the GPU memory and also pay
책상에서 GPU 사이와 GPU 메모리 사이도 지불 CPU와 GPU
attention to floating point precision it might not be the most glamorous thing
부동 소수점 정밀도에 대한 관심은 가장 매력적인 일이 될하지 않을 수 있습니다
but it actually I think makes huge differences in practice and maybe binary
하지만 실제로 나는 연습과 어쩌면 진에 큰 차이를 만드는 생각
nuts will be the next big thing that'd be pretty exciting so yeah just to recap
그래서 그래 그냥 정리해하는 너트 꽤 흥미로운 것 다음 큰 일이 될 것입니다
everything we talked about today that we talked to a date augmentation as a trick
모든 우리는 우리가 속임수로 날짜 확대 술 이야기 오늘 이야기
for improving when you have small datasets and help prevent overfitting we
당신이 작은 데이터 세트를 가지고 우리를 overfitting 방지 때 개선
talk about transfer learning as a way to initialize from existing models to help
도움이 기존 모델에서 초기화하는 방법으로 전송 학습에 대해 이야기
with your help with your training we talked a lot of detail about
훈련과 당신의 도움으로 우리가에 대한 세부 사항을 많이 이야기
convolutions both how to combine them to make efficient models and
회선 모두 효율적인 모델을 만들기 위해 그들을 결합하는 방법과
and we talked about all these implementation details so I think that's
나는 그 생각 때문에 우리는 모든 구현 세부 사항에 대해 이야기
that's all we have printed ASAP is any last minute questions
그것은 우리가 최대한 빨리 인쇄 한 모든 임의의 마지막 분 질문입니다입니다
alright so I guess we're done a couple minutes early and our midst the midterms
좋아, 그래서 우리가 몇 초 분, 우리 가운데 중간 고사를 마친 것 같아요